<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on feelydj Blog</title>
    <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on feelydj Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 17:56:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://feelydj.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>tcp handshake</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/tcp-handshake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 17:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/tcp-handshake/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A TCP connection is identified by a set of two IP addresses and two ports. How is this established? The TCP handshake is crucial in setting up a TCP connection. It performs the initial negotiation so that both server and client can begin to send data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client performs an &lt;em&gt;active open&lt;/em&gt; meaning it&amp;rsquo;s initiating the connection. The client chooses an ISN (Initial Sequence Number) to start the numbering of it&amp;rsquo;s packets. This number is a 32-bit integer which is incremented by 1 every 4 microseconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client sends a SYN (synchronize) packet announcing this ISN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The server (the passive opener) responds with an ACK (acknowledge) which indicates the server has received the initial SYN. The ACK will &amp;lsquo;ackowledge&amp;rsquo; the received sequence number + 1 (essentially it tells the sender which packet the receiver is expecting next). In the same packet the server announces it&amp;rsquo;s own ISN (server and client each have their own sequence).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client then &amp;lsquo;ACKs&amp;rsquo; the server&amp;rsquo;s SYN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point the connection is established and data can flow between server and client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-is-the-isn-chosen&#34;&gt;How is the ISN chosen?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ISN is chosen in a semi-random fashion and along with the time-based incrementation of the number aims to prevent late-arriving packets from an old TCP connection with the same IP addresses and ports from interfering with a newer TCP connection. The 4-tuple (2 IP addresses, 2 ports) is run through a cryptographic hash, along with an additional secret value chosen every five minutes, in order to generate the initial number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;retries&#34;&gt;Retries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the active opener sends a SYN and does not receive a response, it will retry in &amp;ldquo;exponential backoff&amp;rdquo; fashion, doubling the time it waits after each non-response. It will eventually time out after two minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Linux, the default retry amount is 5. This can be set with the net.ipv4.tcp_syn_retries_default variable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Correspondingly, if a server does not receive a response to it&amp;rsquo;s SYN-ACK, it will retry. This also defaults to 5 and is set with net.ipv4.tcp_synack_retries&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notch</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-12-notch-tweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 21:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-12-notch-tweet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were in talks about maybe bringing a version of Minecraft to Oculus. I just cancelled that deal. Facebook creeps me out.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Markus Persson (@notch) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/notch/statuses/448586381565390848&#34;&gt;March 25, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hahaha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there&amp;rsquo;s more on &lt;a href=&#34;http://notch.net/2014/03/virtual-reality-is-going-to-change-the-world/&#34;&gt;Notch&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
And I did not chip in ten grand to seed a first investment round to build value for a Facebook acquisition.
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my presence is a present</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-11-04-my-presence-is-a-present/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-11-04-my-presence-is-a-present/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I accidentally wget&amp;rsquo;d the contents of a Github page instead of the &amp;ldquo;raw&amp;rdquo; link to the file. In trying to figure out what was going on, I found this near the bottom of the file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
    As Kanye West said:
    &gt; We&#39;re living the future so
    &gt; the present is our past.
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahaha.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scripting the creation of new Jekyll posts</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-06-26-script-start-new-jekyll-post-with-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-06-26-script-start-new-jekyll-post-with-date/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t played around with bash so much before, but I&amp;rsquo;m learning by trying to automate things I do repeatedly. I found myself often starting a new Jekyll post with that magical filename format: &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-title.md&lt;/code&gt;. So I decided to try and get that done using an alias, which didn&amp;rsquo;t really work, so I ended up adding a function to my .bashrc:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;function editpost()
{
   vim $(date +&amp;quot;%Y-%m-%d-$1.md&amp;quot;)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I can quickly start a Jekyll post with that title by going into my posts folder and using the command&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;editpost title-of-new-post
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and it will open a file in with the formatted date, the title, and the .md suffix. Fairly handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had originally intended it just for &lt;em&gt;starting&lt;/em&gt; posts, and had called the command &lt;code&gt;startpost&lt;/code&gt;. Then I realised it could solve another problem: it can be annoying to have to tab in the date when you want to edit a post you&amp;rsquo;ve just closed. So you can simply reopen the same file again using the same command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I want to make it add the Yaml front matter at the top with the layout and title for the post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Cosby</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/bill-cosby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/bill-cosby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don’t know the key to success, but the key to failure is trying to please everyone.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>review: The Mythical Man-Month</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-26-review-mythical-man-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2012 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-26-review-mythical-man-month/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/TarPits.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;La Brea tar Pits&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read one book this semester. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be able to read three or four. I&amp;rsquo;ll need to make more time for it. Summer&amp;rsquo;s here now, so I made a last-minute effort to get it finished. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading slowly, chapter-by-chapter, at the weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Mythical-Month-Essays-Software-Engineering/dp/0201835959&#34;&gt;The Mythical Man-Month&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fred_Brooks&#34;&gt;Frederick P. Brooks, Jr.&lt;/a&gt;, was recommended as reading material for one of my modules, but I&amp;rsquo;d heard the name mentioned before, and that&amp;rsquo;s really why I chose that one. I decided to buy it from Amazon as I knew I&amp;rsquo;d never get it back to the library on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is really something peculiar, and in a way, spectacular. It&amp;rsquo;s a product of a very specific time and place and aimed at a very specific selection of people, yet, like the timeless illustrations prepending each chapter, the final product seems to cut across the bounds of the place from which it emerged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s essentially a book about managing software development, structured around a small few central pillars or concepts. But it goes far beyond the managerial waffle you might see in other books on the topic. Each chapter starts with a quote and a central concept which is explored. The book gets you thinking, whether you have any interest in managing a team of developers or not. It&amp;rsquo;s enjoyable to read, and a wry sense of humour permeates the deep thinking. I can imagine it being of interest to managers and engineers in any field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the Anniversary Edition which adds some new content at the end, bringing it up to almost the world of modern computing. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting, though, that these actually seem more dated and less timeless than the main meat of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book ends with a predictions that are by turns ominous and hopeful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The tar pit of engineering will continue to be sticky for a long time to come.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Not only is the end not in sight, the pace is not slackening. We have many future joys.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone doing anything slightly related, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend this as a weighty, intellectual read that&amp;rsquo;s also really enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012-05-13 quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-13-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-13-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;
This is an unofficial, fan made remix album. No copyright infringement or offense intended. Just loving the music. (Don&#39;t sue me, I don&#39;t fucking have anything.)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://thepiratebay.se/user/queeroid/&#34;&gt;queeroid&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>spawn a web browser with a hotkey in Awesome</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-06-awesome-spawn-web-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 17:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-06-awesome-spawn-web-browser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;m getting the hang of Awesome&amp;rsquo;s config file and Lua, I&amp;rsquo;m finding it to be really powerful. Yesterday I &lt;a href=&#34;http://awesome.naquadah.org/wiki/Volume_control_and_display&#34;&gt;added a volume control widget&lt;/a&gt;, and today I&amp;rsquo;m doing something I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to do for a while - adding a hotkey for opening a browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this you need to find the key bindings section in rc.lua. I wanted to have mod key + w open Chromium. This is similiar to something I found really handy in &lt;a href=&#34;http://crunchbanglinux.org/&#34;&gt;Crunchbang&lt;/a&gt;. By default, mod key + w opens another Awesome menu at the cursor, which is something I haven&amp;rsquo;t used once and can&amp;rsquo;t imagine using, so I replaced that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the callback function where it had said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mymainmenu:show({keygrabber=true}) 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I replaced with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;awful.util.spawn(&amp;quot;chromium-browser&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and restarted Awesome with mod + shift + r.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And voila, mod key and w spawns a Chromium.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;I Wish&#39; English trailer</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-15-i-wish-english-trailer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-15-i-wish-english-trailer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/koreeda.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Koreeda&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The English-language trailer for &lt;i&gt;I Wish&lt;/i&gt; (Kiseki) &lt;a href=&#34;http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/magnolia/iwish/&#34;&gt;has been released&lt;/a&gt;. This is the latest film from the extremely talented Japanese director &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hirokazu_Koreeda&#34;&gt;Hirokazu Koreeda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what the plot is (just what I got from the trailer) but going by Koreeda&amp;rsquo;s previous films, it isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be that important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Koreeda&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Still_Walking_(film)&#34;&gt;Still Walking&lt;/a&gt;, released in 2008, is one of my favourite films. The story of that was essentially a man visits his parents. But the result was a textured, and gripping, masterpiece. Like films by Ozu, the stillness is sometimes the most important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Koreeda followed Still Walking in 2009 with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Air_Doll&#34;&gt;Air Doll&lt;/a&gt;, which was a more light-hearted affair. While I found it slightly disappointing, it was good fun overall, and presented some interesting ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibly Koreeda&amp;rsquo;s most well-known film is 2004&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nobody_Knows_(2004_film)&#34;&gt;Nobody Knows&lt;/a&gt;, a disturbing true story following a group of children left alone by their mother in an apartment. I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend this as I found it slightly depressing, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely the work of a great director.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to see &lt;i&gt;I Wish&lt;/i&gt;. It has many of the same actors from &lt;i&gt;Still Walking&lt;/i&gt;, but judging from the trailer it won&amp;rsquo;t be a similiar style. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping it will be just as good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;via: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jfilmpowwow.blogspot.com/2012/04/north-american-release-date-and-trailer.html&#34;&gt;J-Film Pow-Wow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;photo credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/pabo76/&#34;&gt;Pabo76&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;listening: &lt;a href=&#34;http://soundcloud.com/johnnyjewel/symmetry-themes-for-an?page=2&#34;&gt;Themes for an Imaginary Film&lt;/a&gt;. Totally addicted to the Chromatics and that kind of stuff recently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;jekyll: command not found&#39; in post-receive hook</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-02-jekyll-post-receive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-02-jekyll-post-receive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to set up my server so that I can edit blog posts locally and push them to a bare Git repository on my server, which will auto-publish the changes with Jekyll. I&amp;rsquo;m using a post-receive hook to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was getting a weird error that I was stuck on for a couple of hours. Ruby is installed on the server under RVM, and Jekyll is installed as a Gem. I added RVM to my PATH in .bashrc and the &lt;code&gt;jekyll&lt;/code&gt; command worked fine from the command line. So I added a post-receive script that would do some magic and run Jekyll to generate the new site from the updated Git repository after it receives a push. But when I pushed from my local machine, I was getting the error &lt;code&gt;jekyll: command not found&lt;/code&gt; from the post-receive script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution was to add the -l flag to &lt;code&gt;#!bin/bash&lt;/code&gt; at the top of the script. &lt;a href = &#34;http://blog.scoutapp.com/articles/2010/09/07/rvm-and-cron-in-production&#34;&gt;I found this out here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012-02-11 quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-11-quote-richard-m-stallman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-11-quote-richard-m-stallman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
Why is it bad to use an unauthorized copy of a proprietary program?
Because it’s proprietary! So an unauthorized copy is almost as nasty as an
authorized copy of the same program. They are both nasty because they are
proprietary. The users don’t have control over them. If they pay the developer
– that makes it worse, because they are rewarding this delinquency. That’s
why the authorized copy is worse. But they are both bad because they are
both proprietary software. If you want freedom, you have to get rid of them
both, because they both control you.
I don’t use that software. If you offered me an authorized copy and you
wanted to pay me a million dollars to take it, I still wouldn’t take it,
unless I could throw it away immediately. Yeah – if I could take the
million dollars and throw away the program, then I would say yes.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href = &#34;http://rt.com/news/richard-stallman-free-software-875/&#34;&gt;Richard M. Stallman&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012-04-08 quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-08-quote-of-the-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-08-quote-of-the-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote style = &#34;font-size: 150%&#34;&gt;
If you still need more motivation for writing, documenting, or promoting Free Software, you probably have not been at FOSDEM.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style = &#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;http://fsfe.org/news/nl/nl-201203.html&#34;&gt;- FSFE March Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012-04-30 quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-30-quote-daniel-markham/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-30-quote-daniel-markham/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;
You shouldn&#39;t be trying to write an encyclopedia. Every post shouldn&#39;t be a special snowflake. Instead you should be letting it all hang out and letting the system do it&#39;s job.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whattofix.com/blog/archives/2012/03/where-the-net-i.php&#34;&gt;Daniel Markham, &lt;i&gt;Where the Net is Broken&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012-08-04 quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-08-04-quote-john-crichton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-08-04-quote-john-crichton/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;
Well, you know, I try to save a life a day. Usually it&#39;s my own...
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Farscape_characters#John_Crichton&#34;&gt;John Crichton&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012-09-09 quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-09-09-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-09-09-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;
After this work, Left 4 Dead 2 is running at 315 FPS on Linux. That the Linux version runs faster than the Windows version (270.6) seems a little counter-intuitive, given the greater amount of time we have spent on the Windows version. However, it does speak to the underlying efficiency of the kernel and OpenGL.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.valvesoftware.com/linux/faster-zombies/&#34;&gt;Valve Linux Team&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012-12-21 links</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-12-21-links-and-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-12-21-links-and-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A collection of links from the last week or so. Stuff you might have missed that I think is awesome, and stuff you will have no interest in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gamasutra.com/blogs/AndrewGrapsas/20121207/183132/Stupid_Simple_Code.php&#34;&gt;Are you a Lone Wolf programmer?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://torrentfreak.com/kim-dotcom-mega-will-turn-encryption-into-a-mass-product-121207/&#34;&gt;Kim Dotcom: &amp;ldquo;We believe within five years half of all Internet traffic will be encrypted with solutions born from our new API&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/press/releases/eff-patent-project-gets-half-million-dollar-boost-mark-cuban-and-notch&#34;&gt;Notch puts his money where his mouth is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gorillavsbear.net/2012/12/02/gorilla-vs-bears-albums-of-2012/&#34;&gt;Gorilla vs Bear&amp;rsquo;s top albums of 2012 with joint number one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/platform/jamie-xx-55-min-boiler-room&#34;&gt;Deadly Jamie XX mix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013-01-08 links</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-01-08-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-01-08-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some more links from the last couple of weeks. I have over 1000 unread in my feed so some of these are a bit old!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really excited for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekwire.com/2012/exmicrosoft-employee-linux-convert-making-movie-opensource-software/&#34;&gt;this film&lt;/a&gt; as I loved Revolution OS &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ee.ryerson.ca/~elf/hack/realmen.html&#34;&gt;Real Programmers don&amp;rsquo;t use PASCAL&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;em&gt;The easiest way to tell a Real Programmer from the crowd is by the programming language he (or she) uses. Real Programmers use FORTRAN. Quiche Eaters use PASCAL. Nicklaus Wirth, the designer of PASCAL, was once asked, &amp;ldquo;How do you pronounce your name?&amp;rdquo;. He replied &amp;ldquo;You can either call me by name, pronouncing it &amp;lsquo;Veert&amp;rsquo;, or call me by value, &amp;lsquo;Worth&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo; One can tell immediately from this comment that Nicklaus Wirth is a Quiche Eater. The only parameter passing mechanism endorsed by Real Programmers is call-by-value-return, as implemented in the IBM/370 FORTRAN G and H compilers. Real programmers don&amp;rsquo;t need abstract concepts to get their jobs done: they are perfectly happy with a keypunch, a FORTRAN IV compiler, and a beer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Laughed out loud reading this. I guess you can replace FORTRAN and PASCAL with C and Ruby or something.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.h-online.com/open/features/Defence-of-the-GPL-realm-1769121.html&#34;&gt;Fab interviews Bradley for the H&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hpr.dogphilosophy.net/?p=20&#34;&gt;Probably the best episode of Hacker Public Radio ever&lt;/a&gt; - warning: it&amp;rsquo;s long!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hackerpublicradio.org/eps.php?id=1116&#34;&gt;But this has to be a close second&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=171571&amp;amp;topic=25799&amp;amp;ctx=topic&#34;&gt;Chrome keyboard shortcut to reopen last tab? Yes Please&lt;/a&gt; And others.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apart from the dire Linux Action Show, &lt;a href=&#34;http://maketecheasier.com/10-great-podcasts-for-linux-open-source-geeks/2012/12/24&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is a great list of podcasts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013-01-20 links</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-01-20-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-01-20-links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even though I already have my own hosted VPS, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ostatic.com/blog/one-server-per-person#buzz&#34;&gt;this article on OStatic&lt;/a&gt; makes me wonder whether I should invest in a physical one at some point&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/JavierCabrera/20130103/184268/Why_You_Need_to_Drop_SteamXBOXLive_and_Develop_for_the_OUYA.php&#34;&gt;Start developing for OUYA!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d heard about this article a lot before, but never actually read it: &lt;a href=&#34;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424053111903480904576512250915629460.html&#34;&gt;Software Is Eating The World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013-02-03 &#34;quote&#34;</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-02-03-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-02-03-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;
I&#39;d like to say a few words about traditional college grading. I&#39;m sick of it. We&#39;re obsessed with grades because we&#39;re obsessed with data. And yet grading takes away all the fun from failing. And a huge part about education is about failing. Courage, according to Churchill, is the ability to go from one defeat to another without losing enthusiasm.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/talks/shimon_schocken_the_self_organizing_computer_course.html&#34;&gt;Simon Schocken&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013-03-21 quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-03-21-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-03-21-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;
Kratos the furious demi-god, a man defined by violence and psychologically
jammed in that moment of aggressive self-belief right before a post-pub
headbutt, is a wilfully unpleasant protagonist indistinguishable,
dramatically speaking, from controlling a tightly balled fist through
ancient Greece. It goes without saying that it’s great to have him back.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/video-games/video-game-reviews/9916284/God-Of-War-Ascension-review.html&#34;&gt;Nathan Ditum, The Telegraph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013-12-01 links</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-12-01-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-12-01-links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arkos.io/&#34;&gt;ArkOS&lt;/a&gt;, distro that runs on Raspberry Pi and provides web services to replace all of Google&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, blogging platform. Apparently it&amp;rsquo;s like Wordpress but more stripped down. Not so easy to install at the moment unfortunately. Looks nice, tho.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013-12-08 links</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-12-08-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-12-08-links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://esr.ibiblio.org/?p=5125&#34;&gt;ESR ready to ship Shipper&lt;/a&gt;, automating everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.polygon.com/features/2013/12/2/5143856/no-girls-allowed&#34;&gt;Long, enlightening article&lt;/a&gt; about how games have been marketed through the years, and towards which demographics. &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Given enough money, I could make guys buy tampons,&amp;rdquo; says Roeser. &amp;ldquo;I mean, I could figure out something to do with them. It all comes down to how somebody like me, and there&amp;rsquo;s frighteningly thousands of me across the country and the world, creates a campaign that specifically targets an audience.&amp;rdquo; Roeser believes that if the makers of Call of Duty came to him and said they wanted to pursue the female market, it could be done. It would just be a matter of making the message appealing to women and reaching them through the right channels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2013/12/the_problem_wit_5.html&#34;&gt;Bruce Schneier, The Problem With EULAs&lt;/a&gt;. I guess this also applies to closed-source software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013-12-17 links</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-12-17-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-12-17-links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some interesting-looking &lt;a href=&#34;http://sivers.org/ws&#34;&gt;stuff&lt;/a&gt; made public by Derek Sivers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lunchbots.com&#34;&gt;non-plastic lunchboxes&lt;/a&gt; look so cool!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;In our May Premature Evaluation of Deafheaven’s Sunbather, I compared the album to Agalloch’s 2010 LP, Marrow Of The Spirit. In my opinion, Marrow is the best metal album of the millennium (so far), the apotheosis of what had also been, I believed, the best metal year of the millennium (so far) — perhaps a supernova moment for modern metal, in fact. &amp;hellip;  &amp;ldquo;Sunbather is not a better album than Marrow Of The Spirit,” I wrote, “but it is the most successfully ambitious album to emerge from the wreckage left behind by Marrow.”&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stereogum.com/1561822/the-50-best-metal-albums-of-2013/list/&#34;&gt;Stereogum&amp;rsquo;s Top 50 Metal Albums of 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014-10-12 quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-10-12-quote-minecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-10-12-quote-minecraft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what about Minecraft&#39;s future? From Microsoft&#39;s announcement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;
Minecraft fans are loyal, with nearly 90 percent of paid customers on the PC having signed in within the past 12 months.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sentence, Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sentence tells me all I need to know. If you&#39;ve paid any attention to the negative developments in gaming over the recent years, that sentence should send chills down your spine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.osnews.com/story/27942/Microsoft_acquires_Mojang_for_2_5_billion&#34;&gt;OSNews, Microsoft buys Minecraft&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014-12-18 quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-12-18-quote-st-vincent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-12-18-quote-st-vincent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
Entombed in the shrine of zeros and ones
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href = &#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Vincent_(album)&#34;&gt;St. Vincent&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015-04018 quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-04-18-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-04-18-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to dance but lost my nerve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cramped up in the learning curve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href = &#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fiona_Apple&#34;&gt;Fiona Apple&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Android-x86 entry to grub2</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-10-adding-android-x86-entry-to-grub2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-10-adding-android-x86-entry-to-grub2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided I want to try Linux Mint 12 LXDE on my netbook, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedelli.org/android-x86-ics-rc1-review&#34;&gt;keep Android for convenience&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed Mint and Android on separate partitions but of course Mint doesn&amp;rsquo;t show Grub at boot by default, and grub-update doesn&amp;rsquo;t detect Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, to show Grub at boot I had to follow the instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.linuxmint.com/viewtopic.php?f=46&amp;amp;t=55370&amp;amp;start=0&#34;&gt;this thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically you need to edit /etc/default/grub and comment out the line that says
&lt;code&gt;GRUB_HIDDEN_TIMEOUT=0&lt;/code&gt;
and then uncomment this:
&lt;code&gt;GRUB_GFXMODE=640x480&lt;/code&gt; (and set your resolution)
before running
&lt;code&gt;sudo update-grub&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, to add Android to the Grub choices, you need to edit /etc/grub.d/40_custom and add the following: (Which I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://askubuntu.com/questions/109923/how-to-add-android-x86-item-to-grub-list&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
menuentry &amp;quot;Android&amp;quot; {
    insmod ext2
    set root=&#39;(hd0,HERE NUMBER OF PARTITION WITH YOUR ANDROID)&#39;
    linux /android-4.0-RC1/kernel quiet root=/dev/ram0 androidboot.hardware=eeepc acpi_sleep=s3_bios,s3_mode SRC=/android-4.0-RC1
    initrd /android-4.0-RC1/initrd.img
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I changed hardware to eeepc from asus_laptop)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;code&gt;sudo update-grub&lt;/code&gt; and that should be it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android on my Samsung N110 netbook</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-03-android-on-my-samsung-n110-netbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-03-android-on-my-samsung-n110-netbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/android-netbook.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;my netbook running Android&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this on what feels like my brand-spanking new Android netbook. Talk about breathing new life into old hardware - this is really awesome.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found out about the &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.android-x86.org/&#34;&gt;Android-x86&lt;/a&gt; project today via &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.freesoftwaremagazine.com/articles/turn_your_netbook_android_device_android_x86&#34;&gt;Free Software Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. At first I was a bit sceptical about it&amp;rsquo;s level of stability, but I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for ways to speed up my stubbornly sluggish (at least by my standards) Samsung N110 netbook. The project&amp;rsquo;s download page listed releases of Android 2.2 and 2.3 and an RC for Ice Cream Sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grabbed 2.2 (eeepc) first of all, as I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice the others (I was kind of half-arsedly doing it while reading something else). I created a boot USB with UNetBootin and had lunch. Then I booted up my netbook. I was so surprised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had never seen my netbook work this fast before. The fluidity of the animations, the response times, the desktop switching; it was elating. This was twice as smooth as anything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had on the netbook - from Ubuntu netbook remix, to Crunchbang, to Mint, this puts them all to shame. Just using the web browser was actually &lt;i&gt;fun&lt;/i&gt;. It was really like having bought a new Android device. Everything seemed to work exactly as it should, including wireless. That&amp;rsquo;s when I noticed the Android version I had - 2.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly downloaded the release candidate for Ice Cream Sandwich and booted it up. I&amp;rsquo;ve never used ICS before and it&amp;rsquo;s like a whole new OS. But it&amp;rsquo;s gorgeous on the netbook. Most things &lt;i&gt;just work&lt;/i&gt; (there seems to be a problem with suspend and resume but I don&amp;rsquo;t use that much).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll find a lot of bugs quite soon. I wonder about the battery life too. But there&amp;rsquo;s no doubt about how awesome this is. I reckon anyone with an old netbook should at least try this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the Android-x86 team for turbo-powering my Sammy. Really looking forward to just sitting on the couch with this to read my Google reader.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android-x86 ICS RC1 review</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-06-android-x86-ics-rc1-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-06-android-x86-ics-rc1-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/androidx86-review.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Google Music on Android netbook&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ve been using Ice Cream Sandwich RC1 on my Samsung N110 netbook for a few days now, and would like to give a rundown of how it works.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to note, as I mentioned my &lt;a href = &#34;http://feedelli.org/android-my-samsung-n110-netbook&#34;&gt;first reaction&lt;/a&gt;, is that Android is snappy. While the boot time is comparable to the average Linux distro, the speed with which it loads apps and switches between apps is super-fast, and the animations look great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience is identical to running Android on a phone or tablet. Emails pop up in notifications (I love this feature). Sound effects are the same as on a phone, including the satisfying clicks when browsing the web. I’m surprised that all of this stuff works out of the box. Navigation is of course done with a mouse instead of a touch screen, and this seems to work flawlessly. There’s a swift blue glowing cursor which, in conjunction with mouse clicks, replaces your finger swipes or taps. It even works well with the fruit-cutting game (albeit making it easier).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wireless seems to work fine, and detecting and connecting to wireless networks causes no problems. One of those creepy but useful Google quirks is that your Google account remembers your wireless passwords, so you’ll have an uncomfortable moment when you start browsing the web in your mom’s house before realising you’ve never put in the wireless password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suspend and resume won’t work as you would expect it to. For me, opening up my netbook after closing it and pressing the power button does start it up again but the screen stays blank and I have to reboot. Double-clicking the power-button when turned on gives the option to shutdown which is what I use and works fine for me. I believe the kernel can be patched and re-compiled to fix this issue, but I’ll wait for the next RC or the full release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all apps are available, but the ones I have used all seemed to work without any problems, including games. Chrome isn’t available, but this might be because it’s only out in select territories at the moment. Firefox isn’t there, but the standard browser works well for me, even getting my bookmarks and history from my Chrome sync account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Android might be the best OS for your ageing netbook.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battery life is phenomenal. From full charge I got 3.5 - 4 hrs of intense, continuous usage; two hours of Google Music listening, followed by an hour-long documentary, and about an hour of browsing the web. With average usage, you basically don’t have to worry about battery life at all throughout the day. This is a revolution for me in terms of actual daily netbook use, as before the battery life was a constant worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I carry the netbook with me for short spurts of RSS reading and using the Wordpress app. I use it on the train by using my Gingerbread phone as a wifi hotspot. I use it as a music player while I work on my desktop, keeping it running with a pair of headphones plugged into it. I use it to check emails in the morning. I basically use my netbook a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, Android isn&amp;rsquo;t a great OS for when you want to be productive. Similiarly, a netbook, like a tablet, is not a great device to code on, or type. But it is light and small and can be carried around in your bag like a book. You can open it and be doing what you want to do in seconds. If you want to do serious work, you&amp;rsquo;re not going to be using a netbook anyway. Android is the most fitting OS I&amp;rsquo;ve found for this device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even at release candidate stage I recommend Android-x86 be checked out on a live USB. I will definitely be sticking with it for now, and am very excited for the full release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome WM and WWII theme on Ubuntu or Linux Mint</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-21-awesome-wm-and-wwii-theme-on-ubuntu-or-linux-mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-21-awesome-wm-and-wwii-theme-on-ubuntu-or-linux-mint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently discovered the &lt;a href = &#34;http://awesome.naquadah.org/&#34;&gt;Awesome window manager&lt;/a&gt; and so far it&amp;rsquo;s really living up to its name. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that when you start using it you can&amp;rsquo;t imagine ever doing without it. It&amp;rsquo;s like the vim of window management - super fast, highly customisable, and just so&amp;hellip; smart.
I saw this on the Awesome themes page and thought it looked gorgeous:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{site.url}}/img/awesome-ww2-theme.png&#34; alt=&#34;Awesome WWII theme&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It reminds me of Indiana Jones and the Fate of Atlantis. After a bit of hacking I got my Awesome set up like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to do it&lt;/strong&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve put together this guide, like most of the stuff on this site, mostly for my own use, so when I distro-hop or bork my system, I can get Awesome back the way I like it. Maybe it will be of some use to someone.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t have Awesome already, you can install it with apt, and select it as your session at log-in. To get your own config to play with you need to copy /etc/xdg/awesome/rc.lua to .config/awesome/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The WWII theme&lt;/strong&gt;
The first thing I did was copy and paste the &lt;a href = &#34;http://awesome.naquadah.org/wiki/WWII_Theme&#34;&gt;code for the theme&lt;/a&gt; into a file called theme.lua in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~/.config/awesome/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update:&lt;/strong&gt; with Awesome 3.4.11 (Ubuntu 12.04) you need to change theme.wallpaper.cmd line to theme.wallpaper_cmd = { 42 } for this theme to work. &lt;a href=&#34;http://awesome.naquadah.org/wiki/Awesome_3.3_to_3.4#Themes&#34;&gt;More info here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I edited ~/.config/awesome/rc.lua to use the new theme I&amp;rsquo;d created, by changing the beautiful.init call:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;beautiful.init(&amp;ldquo;/home/daniel/.config/awesome/theme.lua&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can restart Awesome to see the effects with Win + Ctrl + r.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next, the font&lt;/strong&gt;
That gorgeous font in the image is called Profont.
I followed the &lt;a href = &#34;http://chrisacheson.net/blog/2009/03/21/how-to-get-profont-working-in-ubuntu/&#34;&gt;these instructions&lt;/a&gt; to install it.
I increased the size by modifying ~/.config/awesome/theme.lua:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;theme.font = &amp;ldquo;Profont 15&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Win + Ctrl + r to see the result.
This made the menus too small to fit the text so I needed to double the width and height values in theme.lua like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;theme.menu_height = &amp;ldquo;30&amp;rdquo;
theme.menu_width  = &amp;ldquo;200&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{site.url}}/img/awesome-terminal-transparency.png&#34; alt=&#34;terminal transparency&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency&lt;/strong&gt;
To get terminal transparency I needed to install the hsetroot package.
Then setting the transparency in my terminator allowed me to see through to the wallpaper (note you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have &lt;a href = &#34;http://awesome.naquadah.org/wiki/My_first_awesome#Change_the_background_image&#34;&gt;set a wallpaper&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows not maximising fully?&lt;/strong&gt;
I had the problem that maximising a window with Win + m left gaps at the bottom and on the right-hand side of the window. Finding the section awful.rules.rules section of your rc.lua and adding size_hints_honor = false fixes this.
Again, you need to Win + Ctrl + r to see if it worked&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome WM and dual monitors</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-07-awesome-wm-and-dual-monitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-07-awesome-wm-and-dual-monitors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/awesome-dual-monitors.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Awesome and two monitors&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently set up a second monitor on my machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well really, I commandeered our Samsung tv. It seems to make sense to have both screens in the same place, since the couch is directly opposite both. The only small downside is that it might be distracting trying to work while your other half is playing Skyrim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was really surprised at how well Awesome works with two monitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After attaching the second monitor, I loaded into Gnome 3 (as girlfriend uses this it was the priority). I used the Nvidia config tool to set up the second monitor and &lt;a href = &#34;http://xkcd.com/963/&#34;&gt;save the results to the config&lt;/a&gt;. There was some setting up to do with Gnome as the defaults were a bit nonsensical; to reach the &amp;ldquo;sweet spot&amp;rdquo; (or whatever it&amp;rsquo;s called) in the top left corner I had to trawl the mouse all the way across two monitors. It was easy to fix with a &lt;a href = &#34;http://gregcor.com/2011/05/07/fix-dual-monitors-in-gnome-3-aka-my-workspaces-are-broken/&#34;&gt;small hack&lt;/a&gt;. There&amp;rsquo;s still some issues I have with it, such as the log out box appearing on the wrong screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I loaded Awesome. There was nothing to do. Just worked. Even stretched my wallpaper across the two monitors. I had to find some panoramic ones to cover the whole two desktops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome treats the second monitor as a second monitor. It gives you another top panel with another selection of tags on the other side, rather than trying to combine them into one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of dragging windows between monitors, you have the &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; cool shortcut of Win + o which shoots your current window across to the other monitor, automatically fitting it into the tiling scheme of the other. This is shockingly useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t see myself leaving Awesome anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash / command line pomodoro timer</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-07-29-bash-command-line-pomodoro-timer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-07-29-bash-command-line-pomodoro-timer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique&#34;&gt;Pomodoro Technique&lt;/a&gt; a lot when I&amp;rsquo;m at home. I find it really useful to not only make sure I get stuff done, but to make sure I take regular breaks and get &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; stuff done, like housework and exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to use a 25 minute timer on my digital watch, which kinda died this weekend. There are Android apps, but I find they&amp;rsquo;re not as immediate and don&amp;rsquo;t work as well. I realised I needed a timer that would run in a terminal, since I spend so much time there anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://navaneethkn.wordpress.com/2010/12/19/simple-egg-timer-on-linux-for-pomodoro-technique/&#34;&gt;this script&lt;/a&gt; with Google. I put it in pomo.sh and did a &lt;code&gt;chmod u+x&lt;/code&gt; on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a couple of problems - first you might notice there are a couple of HTML aliases in there, so I needed to replace them with their symbols &amp;gt; and &amp;amp;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second problem came when I added it as an alias to my .bashrc:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alias pomo=&#39;sh ~/pomo.sh 25 &amp;quot;Pomodoro&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Pomodoro started, you have 25
  minutes left&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Pomodoro ended. Please stop the work and take short break&amp;quot;&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently Ubuntu uses Dash instead of Bash when using sh so I was getting this error after the first minute:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pomo.sh: let: not found
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution was to specify that Bash be used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alias pomo=&#39;bash ~/pomo.sh 25 &amp;quot;Pomodoro&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Pomodoro started, you have 25
  minutes left&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Pomodoro ended. Please stop the work and take short break&amp;quot;&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I type pomo into a terminal and get a 25 minute timer, complete with &lt;code&gt;notify-send&lt;/code&gt; notifications, which look particularly pretty in &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedelli.org/2012/03/21/awesome-wm-and-wwii-theme-on-ubuntu-or-linux-mint.html&#34;&gt;my Awesome theme&lt;/a&gt; I adjusted the display time of these to my liking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2012-07-29/pomodoro.png&#34; alt=&#34;pomodoro timer notifications&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roll on the productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the default browser in Gnome 3</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-26-changing-the-default-browser-in-gnome-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-26-changing-the-default-browser-in-gnome-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes with Linux, and especially Arch, you get so into trying to find a solution to a small problem that&amp;rsquo;s annoying you that when you finally find the answer it can be so obvious it makes you feel a bit stupid. You&amp;rsquo;re usually in a forum somewhere on your 100th googling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d spent about an hour altogether with my Arch box trying to make Chromium the default browser. For some reason links from the terminal were opening in Firefox. I was messing around with ~/.xinitrc, exports, xdg-open and all kinds of things, but to no avail. I finally found a &lt;a href = &#34;https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=118422&#34;&gt;short, self-answered post&lt;/a&gt; with the solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the default browser in Arch was as simple as opening up the System Info application and clicking Default Browser. Admittedly, this is not the first place you would think to look when trying to change a major setting like this, but that&amp;rsquo;s where it is, and still made me feel like I&amp;rsquo;d wasted an hour hacking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/gnome-default-browser.png&#34; alt=&#34;System Info&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drake: Take Care</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2011-11-29-drake-take-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2011-11-29-drake-take-care/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a great album. The thing that strikes you most about Take Care is the confidence and the fresh style that compliments Drake&amp;rsquo;s flow, where before he sounded awkward and ropey. This sounds modern and REALLY cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not throwaway either. It&amp;rsquo;s full of catchy, clever lyrics from the get-go. Then there&amp;rsquo;re monologues, from Drake himself and distant disembodied voices, which wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be out of place on one of the Manics&amp;rsquo; bleaker records, but sonically giving the album a feel closer to something by Burial or Jamie XX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obligatory guests are in place. Nicki Minaj fails to shine but her presence is always welcome; the weight of her entrances is still at least slightly thrilling. These days Lil&amp;rsquo; Wayne is a lot better guesting than he is on his own records, and HYFR (Hell Ya Fucking Right), one of the album&amp;rsquo;s high points, is no exception. Weezy drawls&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
 &#34;confusing me with questions like
  do you love this shit?
  are you high right now?
  do you ever get nervous?
  and are you single? &#34;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reminds us of when he was great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Crew Love, The Weeknd fares a lot better than he did on his debut album this year, thanks to much better lyrics (&amp;ldquo;Take your nose off my keyboard, what you bothering me for? there&amp;rsquo;s a room full of niggers, what you following me for?&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time last year we had Kanye&amp;rsquo;s masterpiece and it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to draw comparisons. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t come close, but it&amp;rsquo;s a great album.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabien Sanglard&#39;s code review of Git</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-05-01-fabien-sanglard-git-code-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-05-01-fabien-sanglard-git-code-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really like Fabien Sanglard&amp;rsquo;s code reviews, even tho I don&amp;rsquo;t normally get
very far before it gets beyond my comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m extra excited to read &lt;a href=&#34;http://fabiensanglard.net/git_code_review/index.php&#34;&gt;his new one&lt;/a&gt;, because
it&amp;rsquo;s on Git.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnome: &#34;oops, I ruined your life!&#34;</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-24-gnome-oops-i-ruined-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-24-gnome-oops-i-ruined-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looks like Gnome have made their own attempt at a cutesy &amp;ldquo;oops&amp;rdquo; message, as seems to be the trend now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While messing around with Gnome&amp;rsquo;s css style and using Alt-F2 and r to reset the decoration, &amp;ldquo;something went wrong&amp;rdquo; and I got a computer with a sad face on it saying &amp;ldquo;Oh no!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/gnome-oops.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gnome oops&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t find it that annoying, though. It&amp;rsquo;s endearing as kind of failed attempt at being hip like a Google product or something. Gnome&amp;rsquo;s just not quite there yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny that I got this the day after reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cooper.com/journal/2012/01/oops_i_ruined_your_life.html&#34;&gt;this hilarious post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grail</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-08-grail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-08-grail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on and off over the last few months on a really fun and interesting project called &lt;a href = &#34;http://leetless.de/grail.html&#34;&gt;Grail&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href = &#34;http://leetless.de/blog.html&#34;&gt;Droggl&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s an open-source engine for writing point-and-click adventure games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/grail.png&#34; alt=&#34;Grail&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you&amp;rsquo;ve ever tried to find an engine for writing a 2D point-and-click adventure that&amp;rsquo;s open-source and cross-platform, but they&amp;rsquo;re hard to come by! Grail is going to fill that gap. It&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I found it I was surprised with how nice and high-quality the demo looked. At the moment there&amp;rsquo;re still some important features that haven&amp;rsquo;t been implemented such as items and inventories, but the code is really clean and extensible and these features aren&amp;rsquo;t far off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The engine is written in C++ and uses SDL. The aim is to have a simple scripting interface for defining a game&amp;rsquo;s scenes, characters, music, and story. It&amp;rsquo;s being designed to be as flexible as possible, so the user interface and other things can be defined by the game creator in the Lua script. Further down the road there will be a GUI editor and tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a simple demo at the moment, and you can play around with the script to see how it works. You can compile Grail from the code over at the &lt;a href =&#34;https://github.com/Droggelbecher/Grail/&#34;&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irssi and notifications in Gnome 3/Shell</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2011-12-18-irssi-and-notifications-in-gnome-3-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2011-12-18-irssi-and-notifications-in-gnome-3-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to switch over full time to &lt;a href=&#34;http://irssi.org/&#34;&gt;Irssi&lt;/a&gt;, as Xchat and Xchat-gnome on Gnome 3 had become too frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed the package from the Mint repos. Irssi is terminal-based IRC client, so the first thing I wanted was to enable notifications. Some Googling led me to &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/irssi-libnotify/&#34;&gt;this script&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install an Irssi script you create a scripts directory in ~/.irssi/. You put the script in there. In Irssi you type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/script load notifiy.pl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to make this load automatically each time you launch Irssi you create another directory inside scripts called autorun. Inside autorun you create a link to the script you want to load automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ln -s ../notify.pl .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted Irssi to notify all messages, not just ones highlighted for me. To do this I had to change the script a little bit. In the line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;return if (!$server || !($dest-&amp;gt;{level} &amp;amp; MSGLEVEL_HILIGHT));&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I changed the message level (type &lt;code&gt;/HELP levels&lt;/code&gt; in Irrsi to find out more about message levels)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;return if (!$server || !($dest-&amp;gt;{level} &amp;amp; MSGLEVEL_&amp;lt;mark&amp;gt;PUBLIC&amp;lt;/mark&amp;gt;));&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and reloaded the script. Every message was now notified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was an issue though with the notifications stacking up in the tray. To stop this I found the section&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;my $cmd = &amp;quot;EXEC - notify-send&amp;quot; .
            &amp;quot; -i &amp;quot; . Irssi::settings_get_str(&#39;notify_icon&#39;) .
            &amp;quot; -t &amp;quot; . Irssi::settings_get_str(&#39;notify_time&#39;) .
            &amp;quot; -- &#39;&amp;quot; . $summary . &amp;quot;&#39;&amp;quot; .
            &amp;quot; &#39;&amp;quot; . $message . &amp;quot;&#39;&amp;quot;;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and added the line &lt;code&gt;--hint=int:transient:1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;my $cmd = &amp;quot;EXEC - notify-send&amp;quot; .
            &amp;quot; -i /usr/share/irssi/icons/icon.png&amp;quot; .
            &amp;quot; -t &amp;quot; . Irssi::settings_get_str(&#39;notify_time&#39;) .
            &amp;quot; --hint=int:transient:1&amp;quot; .
            &amp;quot; -- &#39;&amp;quot; . $summary . &amp;quot;&#39;&amp;quot; .
            &amp;quot; &#39;&amp;quot; . $message . &amp;quot;&#39;&amp;quot;;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing I wanted to do was change the icon that displayed in the notification area from the default Gnome light bulb. I got the Irssi logo from their site and whipped out the Gimp. By removing the text part of the logo and changing the colour of the flame (the black wasn&amp;rsquo;t showing up on the notification background) I was left with this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/custom_irssi_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;custom Irssi logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created an icons directory in /user/share/irssi/ and put this in there as icon.png.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set this as the icon used by the script I had to remove the line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Irssi::settings_add_str(&#39;notify&#39;, &#39;notify_icon&#39;, &#39;gtk-dialog-info&#39;);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and change&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot; -i &amp;quot; . Irssi::settings_get_str(&#39;notify_icon&#39;) .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot; -i /usr/share/irssi/icons/icon.png&amp;quot; .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new icon looks really cool:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/irssi_icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;new icon in action&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more info on configuring Irssi at &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Irssi&#34;&gt;ArchWiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-30-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-30-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided that Drupal is too big and awkward for my blog, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to try something new. Drupal was eating up a lot of the RAM on my 512MB server, even after hours spent trying to optimise it. Also, the updates and module updates for Drupal 7 seem endless. &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.garron.me/blog/multi-blog-site-jekyll.html&#34;&gt;Guillermo Garron&lt;/a&gt; pointed me towards &lt;a href = &#34;http://tom.preston-werner.com/2008/11/17/blogging-like-a-hacker.html&#34;&gt;blogging like a hacker&lt;/a&gt;. This post totally sold me on Jekyll. I&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard about Jekyll before more than once, but the name kind of blended into a mush of other quirkily-named new technologies trendy web developers rave about. This post really made it sound like something that would be useful to me, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;manage with Git, and &lt;a href = &#34;https://github.com/feedelli/feedelli.org&#34;&gt;host the source separately&lt;/a&gt; (this is maybe my favourite feature. Soon my whole life will be in Git!).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;no need to write in a web browser, or write somewhere else and copy and paste into a web browser&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;write in vim or emacs, or any other more natural writing environment - supposedly this might bring me &#34;closer&#34; to my blog, and hopefully will encourage more posting! I want to be able to quickly post smaller posts (microblogs?) without a title and such, and using Layouts might be perfect for that&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;no more comments (this is a good thing for me as I think I&#39;ve decided that comments &lt;i&gt;shouldn&#39;t&lt;/i&gt; be on a blog in 2012 - blogs have a place but don&#39;t do social well)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;lightweight. Faster loading pages (generated static html pages), less memory consumption&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;less to manage - eg. Drupal updates, modules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the downsides is that it&amp;rsquo;s written in Ruby, which I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about, and the posts are meant to be written in Markdown, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t really appeal to me, although I believe plain HTML works too, as long as you add the YAML Front Matter. See, I told you it was trendy. Just check out the site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;img/2012-04-30-jekyll-website-screen.png&#34; style = &#34;width: 600px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently trying it out, and this post will be on both the Drupal instance and the testing Jekyll site. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have it up and running soon. I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on styling it and making sure all the old posts ported over succesfully. Watch this space!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kupfer! rocks!</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-08-04-kupfer-rocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-08-04-kupfer-rocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying out Kupfer for a few days now. I heard about it from the guys at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://linuxbasix.com/tiki-index.php?page=Linuxbasix%20Podcast%20Shownotes&amp;amp;pagenum=15#Episode_104_-_Ubuntu_12.04_Backup_Restore_MBR_w_Ubuntu_Disk_Utility_great_for_v_iew_all_hd_details_Kupfer_Rocks_Real-Time_MOnitoring_Tool_under_Ubuntu&#34;&gt;Linuxbasix&lt;/a&gt; podcast. They gave an empassioned recommendation for this application launcher, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make out what exactly what it was called or how it was spelled. If they gave the spelling, I didn&amp;rsquo;t hear it and didn&amp;rsquo;t go back to check because I was driving. Anyway I found the launcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s spelled Kupfer! with an exclamation mark. And it is great. I was never really happy with Awesome&amp;rsquo;s Command-R run prompt. Sure, it was predictive, but you had to start from the beginning. For example, you want &lt;code&gt;gnome-screenshot&lt;/code&gt;, you can&amp;rsquo;t just type &lt;code&gt;screenshot&lt;/code&gt; and expect to get the app you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But kupfer! does this. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of like the Mint menu or Gnome&amp;rsquo;s search in the way it predicts what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s apparently desktop-agnostic, which is probably why it fits in so well with Awesome. It sits up in the system tray (I don&amp;rsquo;t know why, but in Awesome, nothing looks out of place in the system tray). I&amp;rsquo;ve removed the shortcut key for the Awesome run prompt and instead mapped Command-R to open the Kupfer! prompt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2012-08-04/kupfer.png&#34; alt=&#34;kupfer! in the Awesome system tray&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently Kupfer! learns your preferences and all that. I&amp;rsquo;m loving it so far, but I&amp;rsquo;ll give a more in-dept run-down of how I like it soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get Kupfer to run at startup in Awesome I had to add the following line to my &lt;code&gt;rc.lua&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;awful.util.spawn(&amp;quot;kupfer&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get it over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://engla.github.com/kupfer/&#34;&gt;the website&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s available as an Ubuntu PPA which is how I got it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;postMeta&#34;&gt;
  listening: &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Idler_Wheel...&#34;&gt;The Idler Wheel Is Wiser Than the Driver of the Screw and Whipping Cords Will Serve You More Than Ropes Will Ever Do&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; More simply known as &lt;i&gt;The Idler Wheel...&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lee Vermeulen on VR</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-24-lee-vermeulen-vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-24-lee-vermeulen-vr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
After the demo was over I talked to the Valve employee for a few minutes afterwards about the tech. And while standing and in the middle of a sentence, I had an incredibly strange weird moment of comparing real life to the VR. I understood that the demo was over, but it was if a lower level part of my mind couldn’t exactly be sure. It give me a very weird existential dread of my entire situation, and the only way I could get rid of that feeling was to walk around or touch things around me (or sit down, basically just get in a situation where I wasn’t just standing still like I was in the VR demo). I tried to walk it off but alcohol was really the only thing that made me shake the feeling completely. Unfortunately since I had to get away from the Valve employee having a bit of a existential crisis because of this I wasn’t able to actually discuss it with him.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.3delement.com/?p=332&#34;&gt;Lee Vermeulen on VR&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to recipes</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-12-29-recipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-12-29-recipes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/food/recipes/shepherdspiewithspic_83899&#34;&gt;Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s Pie with spiced parsnip mash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2010/apr/16/yotam-ottolenghi-shakshuka-recipe&#34;&gt;Ottolenghi&amp;rsquo;s shakshuka recipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cavegirlcuisine.com/2014/06/22/bacon-breaded-fish-nuggets-with-tartar-sauce/&#34;&gt;Paleo Fish and Chips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.threebeansonastring.com/notes-on-menu-planning-and-a-recipe-for-grilled-sirloin-salad-with-fresh-herbs-thai-dressing/&#34;&gt;Sirloin Salad with Fresh Herbs and Thai Dressing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2014/jul/30/20-best-summer-fish-recipes-part-3-ofm-paella-mullet-thai-fish-soup&#34;&gt;Thai Fish Soup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/wordofmouth/2014/apr/24/how-to-cook-perfect-chicken-tikka-masala&#34;&gt;Perfect Chicken Tikka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/food/recipes/crabwithmangoandavoc_91733&#34;&gt;Crab with Mango and Avocado&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;roasted-chicken&#34;&gt;Roasted Chicken&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marksdailyapple.com/perfect-roasted-chicken/#axzz3NCaYhQNW&#34;&gt;Perfect roasted chicken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marksdailyapple.com/slow-roasted-chicken/#axzz3NCaYhQNW&#34;&gt;Slow-roasted chicken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pancakes&#34;&gt;Pancakes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.glutenfreeallies.com/blog/2014/7/25/the-healthiest-pancakes-in-the-world&#34;&gt;Sweet Potato Pancakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://paleogrubs.com/pumpkin-pancakes-recipe&#34;&gt;Paleo Pumpkin Pancakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nourishingdays.com/2010/07/fluffy-coconut-flour-pancakes/&#34;&gt;Fluffy Coconut Flour Pancakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pate&#34;&gt;Pate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/wordofmouth/2012/nov/29/how-make-perfect-chicken-liver-pate&#34;&gt;Chicken Liver Pate Recipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;misc&#34;&gt;Misc&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wellnessmama.com/9315/coconut-granola/&#34;&gt;Coconut Granola&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wellnessmama.com/5475/chia-seed-energy-bars/&#34;&gt;Chia Seed Energy Bars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Mint 12</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2011-12-08-linux-mint-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2011-12-08-linux-mint-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Mint 12 for a couple of weeks now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was exciting to install as I&amp;rsquo;d read a lot about how good it was, even if a lot of the news articles and &amp;ldquo;reviews&amp;rdquo; had started to sound a bit forced and repetitive. The general theme of these was &amp;ldquo;The Mint team have done it again&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mint 12 branches into new territory while retaining that polished Mint feel&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/mint-screen1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Gnome 3 Linux Mint 12&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with this. Mint 12, on first impression, doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel polished at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed it fresh, having backed up my old home partition rather than migrate it or upgrade from Mint 11 (I&amp;rsquo;m always wary of upgrading like that). First impressions weren&amp;rsquo;t great. The Mint menu was there, and all the Mint extensions to make Gnome 3 look and function like Gnome 2. But it all felt clunky. The menu looked bad and felt slightly unresponsive. It was freezing regularly. The interface was vaguely confusing. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t Minty at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember how Mint 11 felt when I first installed it. It was familiar, but felt rock-solid and so fresh, and the ease of use and functionality were invigorating. Mint 12 felt more like when I installed &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Looking_Glass&#34;&gt;Looking Glass&lt;/a&gt; in like 2007 as a bored teenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning off all the Mint extensions (admittedly due to frustration) gave me a supposedly vanilla Gnome 3 experience. I tried Gnome 3 on Fedora a few months ago and was horrified by how unfinished it looked. With Mint, Gnome 3 is quite nice. The swipe to the top left corner to switch applications feels really natural and quick. There are still some niggling annoyances resulting from the transition from Gnome 2.x. Most of these have to do with notifications. Xchat bubbles, for example, pile up at the bottom of the screen until you acknowledge them. Most of these problems can be worked around and will surely be fixed soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/mint-screen2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Gnome 3 Linux Mint 12&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall Mint 12 has proven to be a bit disappointing. I think it should have been delayed a bit to make it more polished and stable, instead of what seems like a rushed release to ride the wave of hype generated by Unity deserters. Time will soon tell if it can be improved and match up to it&amp;rsquo;s predecessors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started thinking about installing Arch on my desktop. Feels very daunting. Doing some reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux games: Dead Cyborg Episode 1</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-29-linux-games-dead-cyborg-episode-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-29-linux-games-dead-cyborg-episode-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Endre Barath&amp;rsquo;s Dead Cyborg is a first-person puzzle adventure game based on a free, donation-based model.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not open-source, but it runs perfectly on Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dead Cyborg can be downloaded from &lt;a href = &#34;http://deadcyborg.com/download_page.html&#34;&gt;the site&lt;/a&gt; (I recommend version 002 as it supports mouse look instead of just the arrow keys). To get it running you simply extract it and run one of the four bash scripts provided depending on which suits your needs. The game ran flawlessly for me on both Linux Mint and Arch (there is a package available in the AUR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You start the game waking up in some sort of cryogenic freezer, not knowing who you are or how you got there. As you advance you read messages left behind by your colleagues who had ventured out of their capsules some time earlier, before their deaths at various stages along the way due to radiation posioning. Of course, they somehow managed to lock all the doors behind them and un-solve all of the puzzles. Ah well. The atmosphere is somewhere between quirky and grim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/dead-cyborg-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dead Cyborg&#39;s impressive grapics&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks gorgeous. The graphics are detailed, there&amp;rsquo;s a consistent visual style, and there&amp;rsquo;s a nice big font for dialog. The animations are few but quite nice. You can tell a lot of time and care has gone into crafting the game world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take long to notice that the gameplay in Dead Cyborg is quite simple and isn&amp;rsquo;t going to vary much. It is essentially a game about searching for objects to interact with, some of which are very well hidden. The majority of your time in the game is spent walking around trying to find objects you don&amp;rsquo;t even know you need. There&amp;rsquo;s not much logic involved in solving a lot of the puzzles. Items can be picked up, but not combined, so the combinations of actions that can be performed are severely limited. Often you find yourself moving around with an item active clicking everything else you see in the hope of getting a reaction other than the stock &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s a good idea&amp;rdquo; and an irritating beep sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily a bad dynamic, though. Since the first &lt;i&gt;Resident Evil&lt;/i&gt; clones in the late 90&amp;rsquo;s, games of this type have been criticised as badly-designed because of the illogic of the puzzles. Games like &lt;i&gt;Ico&lt;/i&gt;, and more recently the &lt;i&gt;Uncharted&lt;/i&gt; series, wind the puzzles into the experience and game world so tightly that the player knows exactly what they have to do in a situation, and the gratification comes in finding a logical solution. But it&amp;rsquo;s a testament to Dead Cyborg&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;find keycard A to put in lock B&amp;rdquo; style of gameplay that it survives today and can still serve up an addictive and rewarding experience such as this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/dead-cyborg-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Great modelling and textures&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dead Cyborg is difficult, and advancement is limited to extremely small steps. As soon as one obstacle has been overcome, another one is presented almost immediately. But you don&amp;rsquo;t want to give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is nicely structured. It&amp;rsquo;s subdivided into a series of levels. There is no save system; you pass certain areas, you are locked out of the previous area and given a password to return to this point if you quit the game. It&amp;rsquo;s a clever system that works really well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dead Cyborg is a great experience. It&amp;rsquo;s free, and the artwork and atmosphere it offers are enough to make it worth checking out even if the gameplay doesn&amp;rsquo;t tickle your fantasy. It&amp;rsquo;s a weird, dark, technically interesting piece of software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ending which I won&amp;rsquo;t spoil is quite exciting and has me looking forward to episode 2. There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O_2wCGEV3aI&#34;&gt;trailer&lt;/a&gt; out and it looks even better than episode 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/dead-cyborg-4.png&#34; alt=&#34;A puzzle in the game&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Hobby:</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-01-13-my-hobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-01-13-my-hobby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;browsing odd covers of Call Me Maybe on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/8EjLbVmXIqg&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/dBM7i84BThE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Podcast List</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-28-my-podcast-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-28-my-podcast-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul style = &#34;font-weight: bold;&#34;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
Security Now - &lt;a href = &#34;http://twit.tv/sn&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
FLOSS Weekly - &lt;a href = &#34;http://twit.tv/show/floss-weekly&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
Free as in Freedom - &lt;a href = &#34;http://faif.us/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
Linux Outlaws - &lt;a href = &#34;http://sixgun.org/linuxoutlaws/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
Sourcetrunk - &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.sourcetrunk.com/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
Linux Voice - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxvoice.com/category/podcasts/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
Ubuntu UK Podcast - &lt;a href = &#34;http://podcast.ubuntu-uk.org/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
Rathole Radio - &lt;a href =&#34;http://ratholeradio.org/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSA&#39;s definition of collection</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-02-quote-bruce-schneier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-02-quote-bruce-schneier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indeed, ever since Snowden provided reporters with a trove of top secret documents, we&amp;rsquo;ve
been subjected to all sorts of NSA word games. And the word &amp;ldquo;collect&amp;rdquo; has a very
special definition, according to the Department of Defense (DoD). A 1982 procedures manual says: &amp;ldquo;information shall be considered as &amp;lsquo;collected&amp;rsquo; only when it has been
received for use by an employee of a DoD intelligence component in the course of his
official duties.&amp;rdquo; And &amp;ldquo;data acquired by electronic means is &amp;lsquo;collected&amp;rsquo; only when it has
been processed into intelligible form.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Director of National Intelligence James Clapper likened the NSA&amp;rsquo;s accumulation of data to
a library. All those books are stored on the shelves, but very few are actually read.
&amp;ldquo;So the task for us in the interest of preserving security and preserving civil liberties
and privacy,&amp;rdquo; says Clapper, &amp;ldquo;is to be as precise as we possibly can be when we go in that
library and look for the books that we need to open up and actually read.&amp;rdquo; Only when an
individual book is read does it count as &amp;ldquo;collection,&amp;rdquo; in government parlance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, think of that friend of yours who has thousands of books in his house. According to
the NSA, he&amp;rsquo;s not actually &amp;ldquo;collecting&amp;rdquo; books. He&amp;rsquo;s doing something else with them, and
the only books he can claim to have &amp;ldquo;collected&amp;rdquo; are the ones he&amp;rsquo;s actually read.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2014/03/surveillance_by.html&#34;&gt;Bruce Schneier, Surveillance by Algorithm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix&#39;s open source centre</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-08-05-netflix-open-source-centre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-08-05-netflix-open-source-centre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://netflix.github.com/&#34;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Netflix&amp;rsquo;s custom Github page for it&amp;rsquo;s open-source projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About makes up for their proprietary nature in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python script for creating new Jekyll post</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-12-python-script-for-creating-new-jekyll-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-12-python-script-for-creating-new-jekyll-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Jekyll, there&amp;rsquo;s a small overhead when writing a new post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a simple Python script to handle generating the markdown file with the date and title in correct format on the filename, and the correct headers at the top of the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/create_post.py&#34;&gt;The script&lt;/a&gt; is in the root of the Jekyll directory for this site, so it automatically gets added when the site is built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;python create_post.py the-new-post&lt;/code&gt; creates a new post in _posts with this content:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
layout: post
title: the-new-post
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title then needs to be corrected to be more human-readable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also specify the layout by appending it to the command like this: &lt;code&gt;python create_post.py the-new-post quote&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;2014/04/18/updated-python-jekyll-create-post-script.html&#34;&gt;Update&lt;/a&gt; Script now handily opens vim and jumps down to the required line&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quote of the week: Andrei Alexandrescu</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-25-quote-of-the-week-andrei-alexandrescu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-25-quote-of-the-week-andrei-alexandrescu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
Meh, advice-shmadvice. Who am I to give advice? What’s experience good for in our field? I used to know how to write a keyboard driver and floppy disc formatters with non-standard densities. I’d be all but obsolete today if I hadn’t learned continuously.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class = &#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href = &#34;http://www.serversidemagazine.com/news/10-questions-with-facebook-research-engineer-andrei-alexandrescu/&#34;&gt;Andrei Alexandrescu, Facebook research engineer&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quote of the week: Bruce Byfield</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-16-quote-of-the-week-bruce-byfield/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-16-quote-of-the-week-bruce-byfield/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
However, now that software like KDE development is outpacing proprietary choices like Windows, these basic advantages are more compelling than they have ever been. Increasingly, we are now in an era in which free-licensed software like KDE is not only an ethical choice, but a pragmatic one as well.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style = &#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;http://www.datamation.com/open-source/kde-vs.-windows-7-1.html&#34;&gt;- Bruce Byfield&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quote of the week: Fred Brooks</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-25-quote-of-the-week-fred-brooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-25-quote-of-the-week-fred-brooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;
There are many examples from other arts and crafts that lead one to believe that discipline is good for art. Indeed, an artist’s aphorism asserts, “Form is liberating.” The worst buildings are those whose budget was too great for the purposes to be served. Bach’s creative output hardly seems to have been squelched by the necessity of producing a limited-form cantata each week.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href = &#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mythical_man_month&#34;&gt;- Frederick P. Brooks, Jr., &lt;i&gt;The Mythical Man Month&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quote of the week: Mark Shuttleworth</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-19-quote-of-the-week-mark-shuttleworth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-19-quote-of-the-week-mark-shuttleworth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
So when you next see someone show up on a list and demand that they get what they want or they are going to use &amp;lt;*****&amp;gt; Linux, and how much we&#39;ll miss them because they are really very clever, just recognize that they are not someone who shares the value of the project, we will be better off without their anti-social demands, and look around and appreciate what a wonderful opportunity it is to work with the (fewer) smart people who are also practical, sensitive, and generous. We only need a small number of them to change the world, and we&#39;re doing just fine as it is in that regard.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class = &#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href = &#34;https://lists.launchpad.net/unity-design/msg07745.html&#34;&gt;- Mark Shuttleworth&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quote of the week: Paul Graham</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-05-quote-of-the-week-paul-graham/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-05-quote-of-the-week-paul-graham/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote cite = &#34;http://www.paulgraham.com/hp.html&#34;&gt;
We need a language that lets us scribble and smudge and smear, not a language where you have to sit with a teacup of types balanced on your knee and make polite conversation with a strict old aunt of a compiler.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style = &#34;float: right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href = &#34;http://www.paulgraham.com/hp.html&#34;&gt;Paul Graham, Hackers and Painters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-11-25-regeneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-11-25-regeneration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trying out a new layout.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run an application from the terminal but independent of the terminal</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-30-run-an-application-from-the-terminal-but-independent-of-the-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-30-run-an-application-from-the-terminal-but-independent-of-the-terminal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is something I discovered recently that I&amp;rsquo;d never known before but would have benefit greatly from knowing it a long time ago. I&amp;rsquo;ve realised recently that taking five minutes to learn something new can save you much time and effort in the long run. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of like a real-life implementation of the Don&amp;rsquo;t Repeat Yourself mantra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years it&amp;rsquo;s bugged me that starting applications from the terminal kind-of &amp;ldquo;pins&amp;rdquo; them to the terminal, so you need to keep this terminal open to keep the application open, but it&amp;rsquo;s tied up with running this one application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/pinned-terminal.png&#34; alt=&#34;application pinned to terminal&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve this, it&amp;rsquo;s as simple as adding an ampersand at the end of the command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;chromium-browser &amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: A much better way to do this which prevents the application receiving a terminate signal is to append &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;disown&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;chromium-browser &amp;amp;disown&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting irssi automatically in a terminal at startup in Gnome</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-22-starting-irssi-automatically-in-a-terminal-at-startup-in-gnome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-22-starting-irssi-automatically-in-a-terminal-at-startup-in-gnome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most terminals can be launched with a command that is executed immediately by using the &lt;code&gt;-e&lt;/code&gt; option followed by the command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;gnome-terminal -e irssi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;launches a terminal with irssi running in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be useful if you want to save yourself having to run irssi each time you log in. In Gnome you use the application &lt;code&gt;gnome-session-properties&lt;/code&gt; to
schedule commands to run at login.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the command&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;gnome-terminal -e irssi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and a title and description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now on login you will have a terminal running with irssi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to have the window maximized, you can append the option &lt;code&gt;--maximize&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;gnome-terminal -e irssi --maximize&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating to Eclipse 3.8 broke ADT plugin</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-11-24-upgrading-eclipse-broke-adt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-11-24-upgrading-eclipse-broke-adt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently updated to Ubuntu 12.10 and Eclipse 3.8 Indigo. My ADT plugin was gone, and I was having trouble installing it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was getting this error in the software installer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Cannot complete the install because one or more required items could not be found. Software being
installed: Android Development Tools 12.0.0.v201106281929-138431
(com.android.ide.eclipse.adt.feature.group 12.0.0.v201106281929-138431)
Missing requirement: Android Development Tools 12.0.0.v201106281929-138431
(com.android.ide.eclipse.adt.feature.group 12.0.0.v201106281929-138431)
requires &#39;org.eclipse.gef 0.0.0&#39; but it could not be found
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution was to &lt;code&gt;rm -rf ~/.eclipse/&lt;/code&gt;, then run &lt;code&gt;eclipse&lt;/code&gt; as root and run the update check, and update everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems to have fixed it - I was able to &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/sdk/installing/installing-adt.html&#34;&gt;install the ADT plugin&lt;/a&gt;. You might be prompted to update some SDK packages when you restart but it&amp;rsquo;s fairly straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim keystrokes in Google&#43; and Google Reader</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-15-vim-keystrokes-in-google-and-google-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-15-vim-keystrokes-in-google-and-google-reader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been messing around with Mutt a lot on my server (I hope to post about that soon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got so used to using the Vim-style keybindings to browse my mail that when I finished hacking Mutt and switched to Google Plus, I automatically started using the &lt;strong&gt;j and k keys to scroll through posts&lt;/strong&gt; - and it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;/ key&lt;/strong&gt; also puts you in the search box. There&amp;rsquo;s a list of other keybindings &lt;a href=&#34;http://ansonalex.com/tutorials/google-plus-keyboard-shortcuts/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then I tried it when I moved onto my Google reader, and j and k worked there, too. &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.google.com/reader/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=69973&#34;&gt;There are several other ones&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is pretty cool and useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wacom tablet scrolling in linux</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-12-30-wacom-scrolling-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-12-30-wacom-scrolling-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a Wacom Intuos tablet and was having trouble using it for general scrolling - eg. using a web browser. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to map the lower button to scrolling, the way it is with the middle mouse button on my thinkpad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution, for anyone who has the same issue, was &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thjaeger/easystroke/wiki&#34;&gt;easystroke&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d say the solution is similiar for Bamboo and Touch Wacom tablets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install easystroke (I&amp;rsquo;m using Ubuntu 14.04 and it&amp;rsquo;s in the repos).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the preferences tab and then the button labelled &amp;lsquo;Gesture button&amp;rsquo;. In the window check &amp;lsquo;instant gestures&amp;rsquo; and in the grey box click the lower button on your stylus pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in the actions tab add an action and choose type &amp;lsquo;scroll&amp;rsquo;. Then click &amp;lsquo;Record stroke&amp;rsquo; and click in the lower button on the stylus again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking in the lower button and moving the stylus should scroll now. YMMV. But if you&amp;rsquo;re having trouble making your Wacom tablet work the way you want, try easystroke. You may also wish to go to the Advanced tab turn off the annoying notifications on gesture activation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zenithink C71</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-14-zenithink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-14-zenithink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tablets. Do we need one? Do we want one? I think the answers for me are probably &amp;ldquo;not really&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;d been thinking for a while about getting a new device just for reading feeds and e-books. The desktop gets tiring when all you want to do is churn through feeds. The couch beckons. But the netbook isn&amp;rsquo;t a great device for this by nature. You still have to be positioned in a certain way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought about a Kindle. But the Kindle fire doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be coming out over here, and the other devices don&amp;rsquo;t properly support web browsing. Also, the Amazon devices are probably unacceptably locked down. I thought about a Galaxy tablet or something expensive like that, but in the end I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really justify the cost. I looked at budget tablets such as this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Ainol-Novo-Paladin-Sandwich-Capacititive/dp/B006R6NT6S&#34;&gt;Ainol&lt;/a&gt;, but after some research decided it was too much of a risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end I decided why not just go for that one tablet that&amp;rsquo;s been pushed out in front of me the last few months: the &lt;a href=&#34;http://makeplaylive.com/&#34;&gt;Vivaldi&lt;/a&gt;. Make Play Live&amp;rsquo;s tablet is actually a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Zenithink-C71-capacitive-supported-shipping/dp/B007VNAEF0/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1336975325&amp;amp;sr=8-2&#34;&gt;Zenithink C71&lt;/a&gt; with KDE Plasma pre-loaded. If there is a tablet for me, it&amp;rsquo;s this one. Cheap, open to relentless hacking, and comes with Ice Cream Sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I ordered it on Amazon, and it came to about €100. It was dispatched from Hong Kong yesterday and I hope to get it within a week. I&amp;rsquo;ll post a review then, and following that my experiences installing Plasma Active.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zenithink C71 unboxing</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-06-06-zenithink-c71-unboxing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-06-06-zenithink-c71-unboxing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Zenithink C71 tablet finally arrive about a week ago, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to post anything about it as I&amp;rsquo;ve been away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it a lot, and am really happy with it, but not ready yet to give a full review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some pictures of it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2012-06-06/0-box.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;box&#34; /&gt;
the box it comes in, replete with dodgy Chinese-English translation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2012-06-06/1-packaging.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;box&#34; /&gt;
the mountains of packaging&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2012-06-06/2-box-opened.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;box&#34; /&gt;
inside the box&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2012-06-06/3-plug.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;box&#34; /&gt;
the European adaptor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2012-06-06/4-screen.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;box&#34; /&gt;
the device turned on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2012-06-06/5-connections.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;box&#34; /&gt;
the connections it comes with&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>blogroll in Git</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-06-blogroll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-06-blogroll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started to enjoy keeping lists. Lists of albums I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to this year, lists of films I watch, lists of stuff I need to buy and stuff I need to do (although &lt;a href=&#34;http://taskwarrior.org/projects/show/taskwarrior&#34;&gt;TaskWarrior&lt;/a&gt; is starting to replace a lot of this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the list of podcasts I have here, I decided why not have a list of blogs I read. I spend almost as much time reading blogs as I do listening to podcasts. I think the podcast list has been of some value to some people, which is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One caveat: I subscribe to new blogs a lot more often than I do to new podcasts, so the list will constantly be in flux. So&amp;hellip; Git. A Git-managed blogroll which I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep up-to-date with my Google Reader. The idea in managing it in Git is that I&amp;rsquo;ll have a reference a few years down the line if I want to check around when I subscribed to a certain blog, or to feed a future curiousity about what I was reading back in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep the list displayed somewhere along the side of the site, and hopefully someone might be interested in following some of the links, and possibly subscribing too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;postMeta&#34;&gt;
listening: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Departures_%28film%29#Soundtrack&#34;&gt;Departures&lt;/a&gt; - watch the film and the main theme will unfailingly generate chills
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>chromecast</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-12-27-chromecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-12-27-chromecast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got a Chromecast as a Christmas present and finding it really handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially so after the discovery of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xat/castnow&#34;&gt;castnow&lt;/a&gt; which lets you stream anything to the chromecast from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What really won me over was the option &amp;ndash;subtitles &lt;/local/path/to/subtitles.srt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cool new flask</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-01-05-cool-new-flask/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-01-05-cool-new-flask/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2015-01-05-box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;the box&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2015-01-05-flask.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;the flask&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dedoimedo-quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-30-dedeoimedo-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-30-dedeoimedo-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
asking someone to move from Windows to Linux is not the same as driving car A and then switching over to car B. It’s more like learning to drive a moped, and then be asked to drive a Sherman tank, in reverse, blindfolded while wearing high-heels two sizes two big for your feet, with Kate Bush’s Wuthering Heights blasting in your headset, and no air-conditioning.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href = &#34;http://netrunner-mag.com/windows-user-wanna-try-linux-checklist/&#34;&gt;Dedoimedo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dialogue in Grail</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-09-dialogue-in-grail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-04-09-dialogue-in-grail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had been thinking about how I wanted to get back into coding. I wanted to start committing regularly to &lt;a href = &#34;http://feedelli.org/grail&#34;&gt;Grail&lt;/a&gt;. But when? My week is already pretty full with work and college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d been reading a lot about atypical coding hours on the likes of Hacker News. Apparently the best time to write code is in the early hours of the morning, when it&amp;rsquo;s quiet. I&amp;rsquo;d also read a bit about The Artist&amp;rsquo;s Way and morning pages. Apparently we&amp;rsquo;re more creative when we first wake up, or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning seemed like the perfect time to do this. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to get up every morning, but I&amp;rsquo;m getting better at it. Wake up at 4, write code for a couple of hours, then go to work, or sometimes back to bed for an hour or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;m any better a programmer at this hour in the morning. Sometimes I feel pretty hazy until the coffee kicks in. But it gives me a set time to write code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on is the dialogue system. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to be pluggable so that a frontend for displaying characters&amp;rsquo; dialogue can be easily changed. Multiple frontends can be used at once, for example a subtitle frontend displaying subs while a sound frontend plays the recorded dialogue audio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two frontends we have at the moment are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;speech bubbles&lt;/strong&gt;
The characters&amp;rsquo; dialogue appears floating above their heads in their own fonts and colours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;subtitles&lt;/strong&gt;
Displays the lines at the bottom of the screen, optionally prepending the speaker&amp;rsquo;s name and using the speakers font&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of how dialog frontends are defined in a game&amp;rsquo;s Lua script:
&lt;code&gt;
local subtitles = Subtitles()
subtitles.position = VP(2000,2800)
subtitles.font = Font(&amp;quot;fonts/tommy_holloway.ttf&amp;quot;, 45, 1)
subtitles.centered = true
subtitles.showSpeakersName = true
subtitles.useActorsFont = false
&lt;/code&gt;
And here&amp;rsquo;s how they look in action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/speech-bubbles.png&#34; alt=&#34;speech bubbles&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/subtitles.png&#34; alt=&#34;subtitles&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>excitement about proprietary games coming to Linux - misguided?</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-10-proprietary-games-coming-to-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-10-proprietary-games-coming-to-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2012/05/electronic-arts-attending-ubuntu-developer-summit&#34;&gt;rumblings&lt;/a&gt; recently about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntuvibes.com/2012/05/diablo-3-game-director-on-linux-support.html&#34;&gt;AAA games&lt;/a&gt; being &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=article&amp;amp;item=valve_linux_dampfnudeln&amp;amp;num=1&#34;&gt;released for Linux&lt;/a&gt;. I think the reasons for this can be traced back to the success of the Humble Indie Bundles and paid proprietary games being made available in the Ubuntu software center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admit, there&amp;rsquo;s a little boy inside me that thinks it would be awesome for big-budget new titles to be playable on Linux (this little boy has a lot more free time than me). But when the brief flash of excitement is gone after reading these headlines, I&amp;rsquo;m reminded what&amp;rsquo;s wrong: these games will all remain proprietary software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inevitable will happen: these games will become available on Linux: it&amp;rsquo;s just good business. But they will be obnoxiously big binary blobs. A lot of people seem to be excited about this, and I wonder if people have forgotten that Linux support does not mean open-source. We&amp;rsquo;ve been eased into the idea with the fanfare around other proprietary games being released (they&amp;rsquo;re proprietary, but at least they&amp;rsquo;re DRM free and don&amp;rsquo;t ignore Linux!). Are we blinkered by the fact that Linux is &amp;lsquo;ready for the big-time&amp;rsquo;? Do we just love these games so much that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter they&amp;rsquo;re completely closed-source?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or are games different? The medium is certainly different. Modern games are closer to blockbusters than pieces of software. We go to them for spectacle and story and fun. Most of us own a games console and happily buy silly plastic discs to put in it, while the idea of paying for software on a disc for our desktop has become laughable. There seems to be a feeling in the community that while proprietary software is distasteful, proprietary games are less so. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to tune in more to this in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;postMeta&#34;&gt;
  listening: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visions_(Grimes_album)&#34;&gt;Grimes - Visions&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fiji water</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-01-07-fiji-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-01-07-fiji-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They now have my favourite water in the shop near college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2015-01-07-fiji_water.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fiji water&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fix apt-get and update repositories on TonidoPlug 1</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-09-09-fix-apt-get-tonidoplug-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-09-09-fix-apt-get-tonidoplug-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done this so many times now, and each time I&amp;rsquo;ve needed to google it to remind me how, so I&amp;rsquo;m putting it here for safe-keeping and reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first TonidoPlug (the white one) comes with a custom Ubuntu 9.04 Jaunty image. Unfortunately that&amp;rsquo;s no longer supported by Canonical, so we need to change our repos to allow us to run an apt-get update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First though, we need to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tonido.com/communitywiki/doku.php?id=advanceduses:installing_lighttpd_php_mysql_on_tonidoplug&#34;&gt;fix apt&lt;/a&gt; by running&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir -p /var/cache/apt/archives/partial
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we change the repos by editing /etc/apt/sources.list and change the one-liner to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;deb http://old-releases.ubuntu.com/ubuntu/ jaunty main restricted universe multiverse
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be ready to use nano here because you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to install vim yet :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you can run &lt;code&gt;apt-get update&lt;/code&gt; and whatnot as normal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fix root user in botched TonidoPlug mysql install</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-09-09-fixing-botched-root-user-TonidoPlug-mysql-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-09-09-fixing-botched-root-user-TonidoPlug-mysql-install/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some reason the settings for the /var/tmp directory conflict with a mysql install on TonidoPlug 1, and the root user does not get created. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tonido.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=37&amp;amp;t=981&amp;amp;start=10&#34;&gt;solution for this&lt;/a&gt; is to change the permissions BEFORE installing mysql.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;chmod 777 /tmp
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if you didn&amp;rsquo;t already know this, or forget? You probably know it&amp;rsquo;s pretty irritating trying to completely uninstall or reconfigure mysql easily, and change the root user&amp;rsquo;s password. &lt;a href=&#34;http://stuffthatspins.com/2011/01/08/ubuntu-10-x-completely-remove-and-clean-mysql-installation/&#34;&gt;These instructions&lt;/a&gt; are useful for re-installing mysql from scratch. I did&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get --purge remove mysql-server
apt-get --purge remove mysql-client
apt-get --purge remove mysql-common

apt-get autoremove
apt-get autoclean
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And re-installed with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;install mysql-server mysql-client
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This then prompts you to enter a root password and all that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git aliases for .bashrc or .vimrc</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-12-15-git-aliases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-12-15-git-aliases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cool little trick I just thought of. Shorten 99% of your git commands by putting this is in .zshrc or .bashrc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# git
alias checkout=&amp;quot;git checkout&amp;quot;
alias push=&amp;quot;git push&amp;quot;
alias pull=&amp;quot;git pull&amp;quot;
alias commit=&amp;quot;git commit&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>guardian-eggs-quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-14-guardian-eggs-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-14-guardian-eggs-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
It wasn&#39;t so long ago that we were spoon-fed the unimpeachable &#34;fact&#34; that we should eat no more than two eggs a week because they contained heart-stopping cholesterol, but that gem of nutritional wisdom had to be quietly erased from history when research showing that cholesterol in eggs had almost no effect on blood cholesterol became too glaringly obvious to ignore.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2014/mar/23/everything-you-know-about-unhealthy-foods-is-wrong&#34;&gt;Joanna Blythmanm, The Observer&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>irishtidetimes.com launched</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-02-15-irishtidetimes-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-02-15-irishtidetimes-launched/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Launched a simple project I did for college as a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://irishtidetimes.com/&#34;&gt;Irish Tide Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get the tide times for Ireland by text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s done with Django.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might later expand it offer a JSON API.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>links</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-03-05-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-03-05-links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.osnews.com/story/26726/Jobs_Schmidt_s_Otellini_s_shady_no-poaching_agreements&#34;&gt;Threatening emails from Steve Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.last.fm/2013/01/31/lastfm-desktop-scrobbler-released&#34;&gt;A Linux client for Last.fm!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxandlife.com/2013/02/get-weather-info-in-terminal.html&#34;&gt;Weather in your terminal!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thevarguy.com/2013/03/04/0-a-d-music-shows-theres-more-to-open-source-than-code/&#34;&gt;Open Source games: a great source for Creative Commons music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mathias-dopfner-quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-05-14-mathias-dopfner-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-05-14-mathias-dopfner-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
There is a quote from you in this context that concerns me. In 2009 you said: “If you have something that you don’t want anyone to know, maybe you shouldn’t be doing it in the first place.” The only sentence that is even more worrying comes from Mark Zuckerberg when he was on the podium of a conference with you and I in the audience. Someone asked what Facebook thinks of the storage of data and the protection of privacy. And Zuckerberg said: “I don’t understand your question. If you have nothing to hide you have nothing to fear.”
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.faz.net/aktuell/feuilleton/debatten/mathias-doepfner-s-open-letter-to-eric-schmidt-12900860.html&#34;&gt;Mathias Döpfner’s open letter to Google&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moved to Jekyll, and apologies about messing up feeds!</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-09-moved-to-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-09-moved-to-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So as you may or may not notice my site looks a little bit different. Behind the scenes it&amp;rsquo;s completely different. I&amp;rsquo;ve moved completely over to Jekyll, so what you&amp;rsquo;re looking at now is a static html page that has been &amp;lsquo;compiled&amp;rsquo; by Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move was disastrous. It was the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve tried any kind of site migration. I don&amp;rsquo;t even have that much content here, and the site was already pretty new to begin with, but moving it was a real pain. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into details other than it was some of the most fruitless and dreary work I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done with web stuff. Still, I managed to keep most of the content, despite at least one accidental deletion (I&amp;rsquo;m going to start backing up soon, I swear! Is Rsync the way to go??).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it didn&amp;rsquo;t go off without a hitch, (sorry if you got old posts in your feed!!) but some things seemed to work well such as Apache redirects from the old URLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m ok with the new look, and it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; improvement being able to type posts in my editor of choice (vim), and have them saved as a simple text file. Markdown is even starting to feel more agreeable. The site feels more &amp;lsquo;fat-free&amp;rsquo; now.  We&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;postMeta&#34;&gt;
listening: &lt;a href =&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/R.I.P._(Actress_album)&#34;&gt;RIP - Actress&lt;/a&gt;. Bright electronic stuff
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my favourite albums of 2012</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-12-30-favourite-albums-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-12-30-favourite-albums-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order, kinda:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visions_(Grimes_album)&#34;&gt;grimes - visions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Idler_Wheel...&#34;&gt;fiona apple - the idler wheel&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kill_for_Love&#34;&gt;chromatics - kill for love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_Kid,_M.A.A.D_City&#34;&gt;kendrick lamar - good kid, M.A.A.D. city&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twin_Shadow#Confess_.282012.29&#34;&gt;twin shadow - confess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bloom_(Beach_House_album)&#34;&gt;beach house - bloom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swing_Lo_Magellan&#34;&gt;dirty projectors - swing lo magellan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Channel_Orange&#34;&gt;frank ocean - channel orange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celebration_Rock&#34;&gt;japandroids - celebration rock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/R.A.P._Music&#34;&gt;killer mike - R.A.P. Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So little time in the year to listen to all of these. Ah well, there&amp;rsquo;s always next year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new fishing stuff</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-29-new-fishing-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-29-new-fishing-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Amazon.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green Shakespeare Beta Box
&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2014-04-29/2014-04-29-shakespeare-beta-box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shakespeare Beta Box&#34; /&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
Assorted bits and bobs, and mackerel feathers!
&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2014-04-29/2014-04-29-fishing-tackle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fishing tackle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>open learning: beginnings of computing</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-13-open-learning-beginnings-of-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-13-open-learning-beginnings-of-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an idea I&amp;rsquo;ve had to try and cement ideas in my head as I study for college and to try and document my learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I spend a couple of hours studying a section of my course I&amp;rsquo;ll try and summarise it here, based on notes I&amp;rsquo;ve written. Might not be of use to anyone but me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned today, or at least formally learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/difference-engine-drawing.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Difference Engine&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/CharlesBabbage.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Charles Babbage&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charles Babbage&lt;/strong&gt; came up with the idea for the &lt;strong&gt;difference engine&lt;/strong&gt; in the 20&amp;rsquo;s; a machine to calculate a series of values automatically. It was never completed by Babbage but he created a series of prototypes (two were recently constructed by the London Science Museum).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Babbage then began designing the &lt;strong&gt;analytical engine&lt;/strong&gt; in the 30&amp;rsquo;s and worked on it until his death in 1871. This was a more complex machine; a design for a mechanical general-purpose computer, and different from the difference engine in that it received instructions from a series of punched cards. &lt;strong&gt;Ada Lovelace&lt;/strong&gt;, a mathematician and the world&amp;rsquo;s first computer programmer, wrote an application for the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/AdaLovelace.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ada Lovelace&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Entscheidungsproblem&lt;/strong&gt; is a mathematical challenge posed by David Hilbert in 1928. It asks for an algorithm that will take as input a description of a formal language and a mathematical statement in the language and produce as output either &amp;ldquo;True&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;False&amp;rdquo; according to whether the statement is true or false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turing Machine&lt;/strong&gt;
An abstract machine described by &lt;strong&gt;Alan Turing&lt;/strong&gt; in 1936.
Reads symbols from a ticker tape.
Can simulate the logic of any computer algorithm.
Consists of:
&lt;strong&gt;Tape&lt;/strong&gt; with symbols on it
A &lt;strong&gt;head&lt;/strong&gt; which reads the symbols from tape
A &lt;strong&gt;finite table of instruction sets&lt;/strong&gt; executed depending on state (read or write to tape, go to another state)
A &lt;strong&gt;state register&lt;/strong&gt; which keeps track of which state the machine is in (starts in a default state)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/AlanTuring.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alan Turing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>open learning: finite state machines</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-22-open-learning-finite-state-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-22-open-learning-finite-state-machines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What I understand of finite state machines is that they are graphical representations used to represent states in computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;States are represented by circles. Arrows are drawn between states that represent the input symbols received. One input symbol can be received per transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A terminating state, or a state we can finish on, is represented by a double circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aduni.org/&#34;&gt;Aduni.org&lt;/a&gt; provides excellent free, creative commons-licensed lectures on finite state machines which I would highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re also on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HyUK5RAJg1c&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Things I&amp;rsquo;ve noted about finite state machines&lt;/b&gt;
A program cannot be made which looks at code and sees if it can go into an infinite loop - it cannot be computed!
What an FSM &lt;b&gt;can&lt;/b&gt; do: anything that can be solved by remembering a finite amount of information.
What an FSM &lt;b&gt;can&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/b&gt; do: anything that involves counting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>open learning: modern computing, first generation</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-20-open-learning-modern-computing-first-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-20-open-learning-modern-computing-first-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first generation of modern computing history is said to have begun around the late 1930s. &lt;a href = &#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zuse&#34;&gt;Zuse&lt;/a&gt; in Germany and &lt;a href = &#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atanasoff&#34;&gt;Atanasoff&lt;/a&gt; in the USA developed basic computers. The work of neither was recognised widely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the world&amp;rsquo;s first digital computer, &lt;a href = &#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colossus_computer&#34;&gt;Colossus&lt;/a&gt;, was developed out of the public eye at Bletchley Park. The British built it in secret during World War 2, with the help of &lt;a&gt;Alan Turing&lt;/a&gt;, to decode messages from the German ENIGMA machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eniac&#34;&gt;ENIAC&lt;/a&gt;, however, the creation of John Mauchley and J. Presper Eckert, became famous when it was revealed in 1946. It was a giant machine, using over 17,000 vacuum tubes as binary switches (combined into racks so as to save time in searching for a single burnt out tube). Development had started in 1943 with US military funding. It was intended for calculating artillery firing trajectories but was Turing-complete and could be programmed to solve other problems. It was capable of holding a 10-digit number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/eniac.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Operators of ENIAC holding racks of vacuum tubes&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the above interests you in any way I would highly recommend the 5-part BBC documentary series &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Machine_That_Changed_the_World_(TV_miniseries)&#34;&gt;The Machine That Changed the World&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those really high quality, well-researched and thoughtfully-paced programmes that are likely to be entertaining regardless of the subject material. &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rcR74y61xZk&#34;&gt;You can watch it in its entirety on Youtube.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ownCloud on TonidoPlug</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-25-owncloud-on-tonidoplug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-01-25-owncloud-on-tonidoplug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/owncloud-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;owncloud logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;d been hearing a lot about ownCloud. Really sounded like a way to become more independent as a netizen, and since I was already running my own &lt;a href = &#34;http://feedelli.org/refresh-page-and-restart-memory&#34;&gt;mini server&lt;/a&gt; I knew it was only a matter of time before I&amp;rsquo;d have to install it. But what finally convinced me to do it soon was Klaatu&amp;rsquo;s super-enthusiastic appraisal on &lt;a href = &#34;http://gnuworldorder.info/&#34;&gt;Gnu World Order&lt;/a&gt; (which reminds me, &lt;a href = &#34;http://hackerpublicradio.org/eps.php?id=0852&#34;&gt;Klaatu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s also the reason I&amp;rsquo;m trying emacs instead of vim or gedit for this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing is really simple. I pulled the development version from the &lt;a href = &#34;http://gitorious.org/owncloud&#34;&gt;Gitorious repo&lt;/a&gt; to my web directory. I then had to change the permissions on the ownCloud folder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;chown -R www-data:www-data owncloud/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that I just had to navigate to the site and follow the ownCloud setup, basically involving just setting up a MySQL database and pointing ownCloud to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ownCloud is being quite actively developed at the moment, with commits being pushed by several different developers daily and an active IRC channel on freenode. One cool experience I had the day I set it up was finding a bug in the text editor and having a (temporary) fix applied within minutes (literally) by asking in the IRC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think one of the most exciting aspects of ownCloud is how easy it seems to extend functionality. In particular, I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the RSS aggregator that&amp;rsquo;s in the early stages of development. Time to start looking at the code and hopefully get involved with that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ownCloud: symlink home directory to your ownCloud files</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-04-owncloud-symlink-home-directory-to-your-owncloud-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-04-owncloud-symlink-home-directory-to-your-owncloud-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a handy trick for if you really want to have your files in one place but accessible everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did this on my server because I felt things were getting fragmented between my various home directories and files I had on my ownCloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to keep everything in one place I created a symlink from the home directory on my server to to the /owncloud/$USER/files directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ln -s /home/$USER/ home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to grant apache access to the files so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chown -R www-data:www-data /home/$USER&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then add your user to the www-data group (for me on my server this was root):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo adduser $USER www-data&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>podcasts: Hacker Public Radio</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-20-podcasts-hacker-public-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-20-podcasts-hacker-public-radio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/hpr.png&#34; alt=&#34;HPR Logo&#34; /&gt;
&lt;a href = &#34;http://hackerpublicradio.org/&#34;&gt;Hacker Public Radio&lt;/a&gt; is a lumbering beast of a podcast, dominating my feed most of the time. There are two feeds available - one going back two weeks and another with all of the episodes ever released, clocking in at over 16gb. HPR is epic, and it&amp;rsquo;s also a staple. Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s a consumer of Linux-related content should try to fit it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HPR is very regular, dropping an episode daily Monday to Friday, varying in length from around a quarter of an hour to an hour. The regularity is due to the tremendous effort of HPR&amp;rsquo;s proprietors. Ken Fallon recently relinquished the reigns to Pokey, and the enthusiasm and conviction these guys show to the project is really inspiring. Some of the best moments of the podcast come from the human element - the recent epic New Year&amp;rsquo;s marathon, still clogging up the first three or four slots on my podcast feed as I listen to them bit-by-bit, has already provided me with many laughs, moments of inspiration, and plenty of food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HPR claims to be a community-based podcast and that is more true for HPR than any other Linux or open source podcast I listen to. Anyone can contribute a show, on any topic of interest to hackers (you know the ones I mean). Some of the best recent episodes have sprung from the drive to encourage new podcasters to do something - anything - for an episode. The simplistic &amp;ldquo;How I got into Linux&amp;rdquo; topic has produced some real gems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HPR can&amp;rsquo;t be described as just a tech podcast. It is more of another medium for hackers to express themselves. Hacker Public Radio is becoming a fitting title.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quick update.</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-11-04-quick-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-11-04-quick-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The one-year anniversary of this blog is coming up. &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedelli.org/2011/11/13/refresh-the-page-and-restart-the-memory.html&#34;&gt;This post&lt;/a&gt; was made on the 13th Nov 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back on the archive, the frequency of posting hasn&amp;rsquo;t quite kept up for the whole year &amp;ndash; but it&amp;rsquo;s been fairly evenly-spaced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of things I have been meaning to write about but haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to yet. All still moving slowly through &lt;a href=&#34;http://taskwarrior.org/projects/show/taskwarrior&#34;&gt;the backlog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve renewed this domain for another year. End of 2012 is approaching and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to do up a couple of top 10 lists. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a lot of things, including an Android project. More info on that coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;postMeta&#34;&gt;
  listening: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Good_kid,_m.A.A.d_city&#34;&gt;Kendrick Lamar - Good Kid, M.A.A.D City&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quote</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-03-04-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-03-04-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;
I hate to say it, but I am a very high-functioning bureaucrat who looks after licenses.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxinsider.com/rsstory/77100.html&#34;&gt;Chris DiBona&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quote: Pirate Bay</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-07-15-pirate-bay-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-07-15-pirate-bay-quote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;quote&#34;&gt;
    We’re staying put where we are. We’re going no-where. But we have a message to Hollywood, the investigators and the prosecutors: LOL
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepiratebay.se/&#34;&gt;The Pirate Bay&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>qutebrowser and newsbeuter</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-01-03-qutebrowser-and-newsbeuter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-01-03-qutebrowser-and-newsbeuter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been playing around with a promising new browser called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/The-Compiler/qutebrowser&#34;&gt;Qutebrowser&lt;/a&gt; since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/portix/dwb/pull-request/22/several-cleanups-to-increase-portability/&#34;&gt;demise of dwb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a problem with newsbeuter with opening links using qutebrowser (it was holding up newsbeuter). The workaround was the following script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/sh
# wrapper for newsbeuter

exec ~/src/qutebrowser/qutebrowser.py &amp;quot;$*&amp;quot; &amp;gt; /dev/null 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1 &amp;amp;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(don&amp;rsquo;t forget to make it executable)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then use this in ~/.newsbeuter.config:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;browser &amp;quot;~/src/qutebrowser_wrapper :&#39;open -t %u&#39;&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>qutebrowser lightning talk</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-01-03-qutebrowser-lightning-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-01-03-qutebrowser-lightning-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://qutebrowser.org/31c3.webm&#34;&gt;http://qutebrowser.org/31c3.webm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>refresh the page and restart the memory</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2011-11-13-refresh-the-page-and-restart-the-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2011-11-13-refresh-the-page-and-restart-the-memory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is where I’m going to output everything I want to. Partially it’s to keep track of what I’m doing and thinking, and also because some of it could be interesting to someone. I’m also thinking about a project or two that I want to start and need a place to organise my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is the first post of my new blog. I got it up and running about two days ago. It’s the latest stable version of WordPress (3.2.1). that’s running on top of a basic LAMP stack:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo tasksel install lamp-server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stack is hosted on a TonidoPlug device plugged into the wall beside me. It’s a really awesome little thing – a super power-efficient, tiny little server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plug runs Ubuntu 9.04 out of the box (at least it did when I bought it earlier in the year) but will first try to boot into any OS you have on an external hard drive plugged into the USB. Apparently newer versions of Ubuntu support ARM chips, which is what the plug has, but I decided to give up and revert to the custom 9.04 images Tonido provides after spending most of a day trying to upgrade/install a newer Ubuntu version. The OS is located on a 1TB Seagate USB drive attached to the plug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/TonidoPlug.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TonidoPlug&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but apparently there’s a TonidoPlug2 now, that looks a lot blacker and sleeker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s perfect for hosting a small personal website or blog like this. It’s definitely preferable to remote hosting for what I want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>resetting-xkb</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-04-19-resetting-xkb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2015-04-19-resetting-xkb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was messing around with swapping the Caps Lock key and the Escape key, and this
in combination with using the Colemak keyboard layout ended up causing some confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway it turns out to reset any options you may have set with &lt;code&gt;setxkbmap&lt;/code&gt; it&amp;rsquo;s not
as simple as just running &lt;code&gt;setxkbmap gb&lt;/code&gt;. Instead, the solution for me was to run
&lt;code&gt;setxkbmap -option &#39;&#39;&lt;/code&gt;. Not very intuitive, but there you go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>restore a specific folder using Duplicity</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-06-24-restore-specific-folder-duplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-06-24-restore-specific-folder-duplicity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So backing up is one thing, but there&amp;rsquo;s always the fear of the unknown: how easy will it be to restore everything in the event of a catastrophe? I had a catastrophe last night, and had to get my feet wet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been messing around with resizing partitions and I don&amp;rsquo;t know how but my whole home partition got deleted. I discovered this when at boot Ubuntu started complaining that /home was not present and did I want to skip it or manually recover it. I booted into a live environment and saw that my /home partition was now &amp;lsquo;unalocatted space&amp;rsquo;. Gone. Lucky I had backed up everything using Deja Dup before I started. I created a new partition in it&amp;rsquo;s place and pointed the /home line of /etc/fstab to the new partition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then couldn&amp;rsquo;t boot into a desktop environment because all my config files were gone. I needed to boot into safe mode to restore my backed up files from my USB device using the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After booting into safe mode I had to make my filesystem writeable with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mount -o remount,rw /
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I mounted the USB disk to /media:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mount -t ext4 /dev/sdg1 /media
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to restore everything, and didn&amp;rsquo;t have space either, because my backup contained my whole music collection among other things. I just wanted the home folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used Duplicity to restore just the home folder using &lt;code&gt;--file-to-restore&lt;/code&gt;, the location of the backup prepended with &lt;code&gt;file://&lt;/code&gt; and the location I wanted the restore to go to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;duplicity --file-to-restore=home file:///media/backup /media/recovered
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It copies some signatures, asks for your encryption password, and then restores the files. I then had to mount the new home partition and copy the files over to there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was such a relief to get everything back. Only finally started backing up a few weeks ago. Didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to have to use it so soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>review: Beach House - Bloom</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-06-23-review-beach-house-bloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-06-23-review-beach-house-bloom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2012-06-23-beach-house-primavera.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beach house at Primavera 2012&#34; /&gt;
&lt;span class = &#34;photoAttribute&#34;&gt;photo by &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/davenirvana/&#34;&gt;David Tombilla&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only one feeling a bit tense about where &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Victoria_Legrand&#34;&gt;Victoria&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href = &#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beach_House_(band)&#34;&gt;Beach House&lt;/a&gt; were going to go with the new album. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teen_Dream&#34;&gt;Teen Dream&lt;/a&gt; was the kind of album that felt like a full stop. It was precursored by other tentative efforts, but with Teen Dream they had finally &amp;lsquo;arrived&amp;rsquo;. It stood head and shoulders above anything they&amp;rsquo;d done before. I wondered if they&amp;rsquo;d try to keep up with the ever changing landscape of pop, and feeling they were &amp;lsquo;done with&amp;rsquo; the Teen Dream sound, venture into new lands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well it seems like with Bloom, they&amp;rsquo;re happy to stay right where they are, and are showing that they can. Bloom feels like a direct continuation of their last album, but with very natural and slight evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s weird that they can produce the same dreamy mood again, shattering the illusion that it was a fleeting thing to be captured, and shows that it&amp;rsquo;s a particular palette, technical skill, and flair, that produces their songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no real answer to Teen Dream&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U_t5vR1U9AU&#34;&gt;Take Care&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ciHpW0rlKcM&#34;&gt;Norway&lt;/a&gt; here, but a lot of the songs sound ever so slightly sharper and more poppy. Overall the album is really satisfying. It definitely works as a replacement to Teen Dream, which is just about starting to feel overplayed. Bloom arrived just on time. I think their next will have to be a bit different to keep my interest though. They&amp;rsquo;ve changed just about enough. Which is fine. They are a slow-moving creature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>review: Zenithink C71</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-07-08-review-zenithink-c71/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-07-08-review-zenithink-c71/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2012-07-15/zenithink_c71.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Zenithink C71&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/2012/06/06/zenithink-c71-unboxing.html&#34;&gt;bought a Zenithink C71&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt;. Much more than I had expected to. I wanted it simply because it was cheap and wanted to play with it, and maybe install &lt;a href=&#34;http://plasma-active.org/&#34;&gt;KDE Plasma Active&lt;/a&gt; on it (as this is the device they use for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://makeplaylive.com/&#34;&gt;Vivaldi&lt;/a&gt; tablets). I&amp;rsquo;m still using the rooted Ice Cream Sandwich it came with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tablet doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem cheap to look at, but on closer inspection it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hold up quite so well. The device feels light but slightly plasticy and bendy. The screen wobbles and blurs in certain areas if you apply pressure accidentally. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me too much though, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to be gentle with it. There&amp;rsquo;s a piece of dirt under the screen though, which is annoying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battery life is what you would expect - a few hours of use and a few days of standby. This didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like much to me compared to a higher end tablet and thought it might be a problem. It&amp;rsquo;s not, at all. It lasts a longer than my phone and spends most of it&amp;rsquo;s time near the charger anyway. Not always plugged in as the supplied charger is pretty damn short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android 4.0 performs well. It&amp;rsquo;s not lighting fast when you&amp;rsquo;ve got a few things on the go, but it&amp;rsquo;s satisfactory. The screen can be a bit slow to come on and show you the unlock screen when you press the power button. Live wallpapers can be a bit juddery for a few seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cheap Chinese tablet has almost completely replaced the functionality of my desktop and my netbook when it comes to &amp;lsquo;consuming content&amp;rsquo;. I use the Google Reader app, which works brilliantly. The swipe feature to get to the next post is really satisfying. There was a bug with this when I first used it, which caused minor frustration sometimes, but this was ironed out with an update, and the Reader app gets plenty of updates from Google. The app lays itself out differently depending on the tablet&amp;rsquo;s orientation, but both layouts are useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tablet wins because of its size and shape. It&amp;rsquo;s like a book. Easy to carry around in a bag and not have to worry about breaking it. It comes with a slip-on carrier case. It&amp;rsquo;s always near me for quick fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>screenshots in Awesome WM</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-12-screenshots-in-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-12-screenshots-in-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Latest thing added to my Awesome: screenshot functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanilla Awesome doesn&amp;rsquo;t do anything when you press the print screen key. It&amp;rsquo;s been one of those things that&amp;rsquo;s been a minor annoyance, but fixing it got left by the wayside because obviously if I was taking a screenshot I was doing something much more interesting&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again Lua and Awesome make this fun to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In rc.lua, I went to the section with my keys (searching for awful.key), and added the following line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code style=&#34;font-size: 0.7em&#34;&gt;awful.key({ }, &amp;ldquo;Print&amp;rdquo;, function () awful.util.spawn(&amp;ldquo;gnome-screenshot&amp;rdquo;) end),&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like gnome-screenshot but that can be replaced with your screenshotter of choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the label for your Print Screen key - &amp;ldquo;Print&amp;rdquo; here - may be different. You can find out by running xev and pressing your Print Screen key and checking the output.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>smash_turns_20</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-09-smash_turns_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-09-smash_turns_20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;quote&#34;&gt;
“One night I was driving home and didn’t want to go in the house because I didn’t want to stop listening to [Smash]. I started circling the block listening to the record over and over on ten in my old Volvo station wagon. My wife greeted me at the door, and I said, ’Honey, we’re gonna be rich.’”
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteAttribute&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href = &#34;http://www.stereogum.com/1674083/smash-turns-20/franchises/the-anniversary/&#34;&gt;The Offspring&#39;s &lt;i&gt;Smash&lt;/i&gt; turns 20&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>software in use</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-06-software-in-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-06-software-in-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;operating system: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu 14.10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;window manager: &lt;a href=&#34;http://i3wm.org/&#34;&gt;i3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;notifications: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.knopwob.org/dunst/index.html&#34;&gt;Dunst&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robm/dzen&#34;&gt;dzen2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;browser: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fanglingsu.github.io/vimb/&#34;&gt;vimb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;terminal: &lt;a href=&#34;http://software.schmorp.de/pkg/rxvt-unicode.html&#34;&gt;rxvt-unicode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;text editor: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vim.org/&#34;&gt;vim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vim.org/&#34;&gt;gvim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;email: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mutt.org/&#34;&gt;mutt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://offlineimap.org/&#34;&gt;offlineimap&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mykolab.com/&#34;&gt;mykolab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;organiser/calendar: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.roaringpenguin.com/products/remind&#34;&gt;remind&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&#34;http://pessimization.com/software/wyrd/&#34;&gt;wyrd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;notes: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vim.org/scripts/script.php?script_id=2226&#34;&gt;vimwiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pdf viewer: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mupdf.com/&#34;&gt;mupdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;instant messenger: &lt;a href=&#34;https://telegram.org/&#34;&gt;telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;irc: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.weechat.org/&#34;&gt;weechat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;music: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cmus.github.io/&#34;&gt;cmus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;torrents: &lt;a href=&#34;http://deluge-torrent.org/&#34;&gt;deluge-console&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>something I never thought I&#39;d have to google</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-05-04-something-i-never-thought-id-have-to-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-05-04-something-i-never-thought-id-have-to-google/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/hh850437.aspx&#34;&gt;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/hh850437.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>split an mkv file in two</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-24-split-mkv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-24-split-mkv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found a handy little tool called mkvmerge. On Ubuntu and derivatives it&amp;rsquo;s in a package called mkvtoolnix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s handy for when you need to split an mkv file up to get it onto a FAT32 filesytem such as on an iPod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can specify when you want the split to occur, or after how many gigs or whatever. This is how I used it to split a file roughly in half (after 3 GB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkvmerge -o output.mkv --split size:3g input.mkv&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tool works suprisingly fast and gives you two mkv files, which can then be transferred (albeit slowly on my system) to the storage device.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ssh connection freezing</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-14-ssh-connection-freezing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-03-14-ssh-connection-freezing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d noticed that when ssh&amp;rsquo;ed into my Media Temple server, if I left the terminal alone for a while (a minute or two), when I came back the connection would be frozen and I&amp;rsquo;d have to close the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched for a resolution and found it &lt;a href = &#34;http://shapeshed.com/prevent_your_ssh_connection_from_freezing/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a file in my ~/.ssh folder called &lt;code&gt;config&lt;/code&gt; and added the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
ServerAliveCountMax 3&lt;br&gt;
ServerAliveInterval 10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solved the problem for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>starting Midnight Commander in a terminal with Awesome WM</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-13-starting-midnight-commander-in-a-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-05-13-starting-midnight-commander-in-a-terminal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted a shortcut to launch a file manager using WIN-F, sort of like with &lt;a href=&#34;http://crunchbanglinux.org/&#34;&gt;Crunchbang&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m slowly trying to get used to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.midnight-commander.org/&#34;&gt;Midnight Commander&lt;/a&gt; as my file manager, instead of Nautilus. So I needed a terminal to launch with mc running. Sounds easy, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was seeing a weird bug with mc not filling the terminal when running it as a parameter to a terminal command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;terminator -e mc was giving me
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/terminator-mc.png&#34; alt=&#34;terminator with midnight commander&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;while&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gnome-terminal -e mc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gave me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/gnome-terminal-mc.png&#34; alt=&#34;gnome-terminal with midnight commander&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xterm gave something similiar as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seemed to work fine on Gnome, so it was something Awesome related, possiby to fo with Awesome resizing the window AFTER mc had sized itself, leaving it with the wrong size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I thought maybe there was some way to make it start after the window had been resized. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a way to do that, but found a simple solution - just make it wait a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for terminator the command became&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;terminator -e &#39;sleep 0.1; mc&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and for gnome-terminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gnome-terminal -x bash -c &#39;sleep 0.1; mc&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives Awesome time to resize the window and Midnight Commander then can size itself to fill the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then I just added&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;awful.key({ modkey,           }, &amp;quot;f&amp;quot;, function () awful.util.spawn(&amp;quot;terminator -e &#39;sleep 0.1; mc&#39;&amp;quot;) end),
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to my key bindings section of rc.lua.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>switched to Drupal 7</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2011-11-20-switched-to-drupal-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2011-11-20-switched-to-drupal-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve changed over to Drupal 7. Wordpress just felt&amp;hellip; boring. Also I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it could really provide everything I need as I want to experiment with hosting stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had forgotten how frustrating it can be trying to manage themes and modules on Drupal. I finally have the site looking/working the way I want it but it took a lot of messing around. I&amp;rsquo;m using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://drupal.org/project/corolla&#34;&gt;Corolla&lt;/a&gt; theme which is apparently a &amp;ldquo;sub-theme&amp;rdquo; of &lt;a href=&#34;http://drupal.org/project/adaptivetheme&#34;&gt;AdaptiveTheme&lt;/a&gt; which needs to be installed first. I didn&amp;rsquo;t read the readme to see this and ended up getting a php error on my main page after installing it. So I had to manually extract the AT Core theme into the themes folder. Corolla is nice though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of options and settings with Drupal but it seems intuitive enough so far and the interface looks really slick. I&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the annoyance of providing lecture notes in ppt format</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-02-24-annoyance-of-not-releasing-pdf-lecture-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2013-02-24-annoyance-of-not-releasing-pdf-lecture-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was downloading a lot of lecture notes to read through. The majority of these were put on Moodle in Powerpoint format. This is an awful thing to do. It was making me hate LibreOffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started converting them to pdf format to read with the excellent document viewer in Ubuntu 12.04 (which even has some vim-like keybindings). I found out a nice way of doing this at the command line &lt;a href=&#34;http://askubuntu.com/questions/11130/how-can-i-convert-a-ppt-to-a-pdf-from-the-command-line&#34;&gt;at AskUbuntu&lt;/a&gt; (a great resource!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a script I&amp;rsquo;ve been using to convert all the .ppt or .pptx files in a folder to pdf and remove the originals. This uses LibreOffice to do the heavy lifting but hides it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/bash
/usr/bin/libreoffice --headless --invisible --convert-to pdf *.pptx *.ppt \
&amp;amp;&amp;amp; rm -f *.pptx *.ppt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the quest for the perfect music player</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-08-03-the-quest-for-the-perfect-music-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-08-03-the-quest-for-the-perfect-music-player/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at a lot of music players on Linux over the years. I recently come to the conclusion that &lt;em&gt;they&amp;rsquo;re all crap&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People want different things from their music player, which are very personal to them (&amp;ldquo;why on earth would they not have an option to x?!?!?! Do these people even listen to music?!?!&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only player I&amp;rsquo;d ever been happy with was Amarok, but then they went and ruined that, and besides, it&amp;rsquo;s too KDE-specific. In my frustration, a thought occurred to me. A lot of things work better with command line tools. Why not a music player?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of Googling for &amp;ldquo;ncurses-based music player&amp;rdquo; and the like I finally chose &lt;a href=&#34;http://cmus.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;cmus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/2012-08-03/cmus.png&#34; alt=&#34;cmus&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really works. It&amp;rsquo;s a fully functional command line based music player, with nifty keyboard shortcuts (such as, yes, / to search). It&amp;rsquo;s damn cool. Most importantly, it can scrobble to last.fm (and libre.fm).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could this be my perfect music player? I&amp;rsquo;ll have to try living with it. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll do a more hands-on review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;postMeta&#34;&gt;
  listening: the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twin_shadow&#34;&gt;Twin Shadow&lt;/a&gt; is awesome
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>updated Python script for creating new Jekyll post</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-18-updated-python-jekyll-create-post-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-18-updated-python-jekyll-create-post-script/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I posted recently about my &lt;a href=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/2014/04/12/python-script-for-creating-new-jekyll-post.html&#34;&gt;nifty new script&lt;/a&gt; for creating new Jekyll posts quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve updated this now to open vim (you can tailor this to your preferred text editor) and edit the Markdown file you&amp;rsquo;ve just created. It will also jump down to the line where you start typing your post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/create_post.py&#34;&gt;Script is here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>updated podcast list</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-06-08-update-podcast-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-06-08-update-podcast-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/2012/01/28/my-podcast-list.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems to have gotten smaller. Some have finished, some have gone downhill in terms of quality, and some I don&amp;rsquo;t have time for anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vim delete inside brackets</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-17-vim-delete-inside-brackets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2014-04-17-vim-delete-inside-brackets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Been using vim for a few years but today finally learned the handy &amp;ldquo;delete inside brackets&amp;rdquo; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the command is di (delete inside) and then the characters you want to delete inside&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so to delete the &amp;ldquo;parameter&amp;rdquo; in &lt;code&gt;super(parameter)&lt;/code&gt; it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;di(&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and &lt;code&gt;di&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; to delete a word or sentence in quotes but keep the quotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>why I use Duck Duck Go</title>
      <link>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-15-why-i-use-duck-duck-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://feelydj.github.io/post/2012-02-15-why-i-use-duck-duck-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like a lot of others I&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;switched&amp;rdquo; from using Google to using &lt;a href = &#34;http://duckduckgo.com/&#34;&gt;Duck Duck Go&lt;/a&gt; as my default search engine. I just want to mention what I think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://feelydj.github.io/img/DuckDuckGo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Duck Duck Go&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, I have to say that Duck Duck Go is slower than Google. Most of us &amp;ldquo;power users&amp;rdquo; can probably have something googled in a second or two at most after it pops into our heads. That&amp;rsquo;s why the fraction of a second it takes for Duck Duck Go to return a search is noticeable. Let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, Duck Duck Go is never going to be able to match Google for speed. But in the long run, that half a second is only a minor annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duck Duck Go is constantly surprising me with it&amp;rsquo;s common sense usefulness (try &amp;ldquo;what is my ip&amp;rdquo;). But the major reason I use Duck Duck Go is the bang syntax. I find it so useful and it really does speed me up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching Wikipedia is as simple as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;!w beyonce 4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rotten Tomatoes is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;!rt Drive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and so on. I&amp;rsquo;m always discovering new ones that are handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the one I use 90% of the time, and the reason I haven&amp;rsquo;t &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; switched to Duck Duck Go is &lt;code&gt;!g&lt;/code&gt; to google something. Just as fast as a normal Google search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I highly recommend switching your browser&amp;rsquo;s default search engine to Duck Duck Go just to try it, and dive into the &lt;a href = &#34;http://duckduckgo.com/bang.html&#34;&gt;bang syntax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>